<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Modelling group navigation: transitive social structures improve navigational performance</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0213</url>
<snippet>Collective navigation demands that group members reach consensus on which path to follow, a task that might become more challenging when the group's members have different social connections. Group decision-making mechanisms have been studied successfully in the past using individual-based modelling, although many of these studies have neglected the role of social connections between the group's interacting members. Nevertheless, empirical studies have demonstrated that individual recognition, previous shared experiences and inter-individual familiarity can influence the cohesion and the dynamics of the group as well as the relative spatial positions of specific individuals within it. Here, we use models of collective motion to study the impact of social relationships on group navigation by introducing social network structures into a model of collective motion. Our results show that groups consisting of equally informed individuals achieve the highest level of accuracy when they are hierarchically organized with the minimum number of preferred connections per individual. We also observe that the navigational accuracy of a group will depend strongly on detailed aspects of its social organization. More specifically, group navigation does not only depend on the underlying social relationships, but also on how much weight leading individuals put on following others. Also, we show that groups with certain social structures can compensate better for an increased level of navigational error. The results have broader implications for studies on collective navigation and motion because they show that only by considering a group's social system can we fully elucidate the dynamics and advantages of joint movements.
WOS:000358824600023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Balancing the strength of external and internal tie for tacit knowledge management</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09537325.2020.1714025</url>
<snippet>From external and internal perspective, this research constructs the model regarding tie strength and tacit knowledge management based on social network theory. To test the proposed model, this study disposes and analyses the data captured from 301 emerging firms located in Chinese large cities. The results confirm the proposition that both external and internal tie strength impose a positive effect on the process of tacit knowledge management. In addition, temperate internal tie strength positively affects the relationship between external tie strength and tacit knowledge acquisition, while excessive internal tie strength negatively moderates this relationship. This study not only expands the theoretical space in the field of social networks and knowledge management, but also provides guidance for the enterprise's relationship network management and innovation practice.
WOS:000507421600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Social Movements and Social Networks: Introduction</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/14742837.2013.862787</url>
<snippet>In this Introduction we provide a brief literature review of work on social networks and social movements, a brief introduction to certain key concepts and debates in social network analysis, and a brief introduction to the articles which follow in the special issue.
WOS:000341581500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>General and health-related social media use among adults with children in the household: Findings from a national survey in the United States</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2021.07.003</url>
<snippet>Objective: Examine predictors of social media use among a nationally representative sample of adults with children in the household. Methods: Data were collected from the Health Information National Trends (HINTS) Survey from 2017 to 2020 (N = 3559). Multivariate logistic regression models assessed the association between sociodemographic variables and social networking site (SNS) use, SNS use to share health information, participation in online forum or support groups for health issues and watching health-related videos on YouTube. Results: Older adults and men were significantly less likely to use social media (p &lt; .05). Non-Hispanic African American (aOR: 1.83; 95&#37;CI: 1.30-2.57), Hispanic (aOR: 2.16; 95&#37;CI: 1.56-2.99), and Asian (aOR: 2.82; 95&#37;CI: 1.67-4.75) adults were more likely to watch health-related videos on YouTube. Conclusions: Racial/ethnic minorities with children in the household were more likely to seek health information on YouTube, highlighting opportunities to disseminate culturally relevant, accurate messages on the platform. Effective health communication targeted to specific demographics can help counter misinformation and promote health behavior particularly during public health emergencies. Practice Implications: Providers need to foster trust so that patients are comfortable to ask questions in addition to seeking information online. Providers can direct patients to credible resources to counter misinformation exposure and promote healthy behavior. (C) 2021 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000820505900016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>The Impact of CEO Characteristics on the International Entrepreneurship of Small Island-Based Firms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.24043/isj.406</url>
<snippet>This paper examines the impact of CEO characteristics on the International Entrepreneurship (IE) of listed island-based firms (IBFs) during the period 2009-2018. The research considers 164 companies from a sample of eight small islands with securities exchanges including more than one firm headquartered on the island. The selected islands are: Barbados, Cyprus, Fiji, Iceland, Jamaica, Malta, Mauritius, and Trinidad &amp; Tobago. Framed on the upper echelons theory and social network theory, the influence on IE of CEO's tenure, academic background and achievement, family allegiance, and international exposure is studied, taking into account the small island particularities. Through a binary probit model, it is concluded that CEOs' family allegiance, tenure, and academic background (if the CEO majored in Business Administration, Finance, Accounting, or Economics) are negatively related with IE, while CEOs' academic achievement and international exposure are positively associated with IE. Some of these results are atypical in the existing literature; nevertheless, islandness can explain these results. The conclusions attained suggest new theoretical and empirical lines of IE research for IBFs.
WOS:001164467000004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>The Microrelations of Urban Governance: Dynamics of Patronage and Partnership</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/709250</url>
<snippet>The classic urban ecological paradigm envisioned the articulation of the social organization of neighborhoods with that of the city as a whole. This article offers novel empirical evidence in support of this proposition. We analyze the microrelations of governance across two key urban domains, politics and nonprofit organizations, and identify the district-based politician as a key actor linking neighborhood-based and citywide forms of social organization. Using data of contracts allocated by city council members to nonprofits in New York City, analysis of the social network system linking these two types of actors shows two distinct relational dynamics: apatronage dynamiccharacterized by exclusive and long-lasting relationships between a council member and his/her local constituency and apartnership dynamiccharacterized by citywide relationships that are short-lived and fostered by organizational differentiation and embeddedness. Furthermore, politicians and nonprofits differently accommodate the copresence of these two models of resource allocation.
WOS:000542962900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Influence of number of individuals and observations per individual on a model of community structure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0252471</url>
<snippet>Social network analysis is increasingly applied to understand animal groups. However, it is rarely feasible to observe every interaction among all individuals in natural populations. Studies have assessed how missing information affects estimates of individual network positions, but less attention has been paid to metrics that characterize overall network structure such as modularity, clustering coefficient, and density. In cases such as groups displaying fission-fusion dynamics, where subgroups break apart and rejoin in changing conformations, missing information may affect estimates of global network structure differently than in groups with distinctly separated communities due to the influence single individuals can have on the connectivity of the network. Using a bat maternity group showing fission-fusion dynamics, we quantify the effect of missing data on global network measures including community detection. In our system, estimating the number of communities was less reliable than detecting community structure. Further, reliably assorting individual bats into communities required fewer individuals and fewer observations per individual than to estimate the number of communities. Specifically, our metrics of global network structure (i.e., graph density, clustering coefficient, R-com) approached the 'real' values with increasing numbers of observations per individual and, as the number of individuals included increased, the variance in these estimates decreased. Similar to previous studies, we recommend that more observations per individual should be prioritized over including more individuals when resources are limited. We recommend caution when making conclusions about animal social networks when a substantial number of individuals or observations are missing, and when possible, suggest subsampling large datasets to observe how estimates are influenced by sampling intensity. Our study serves as an example of the reliability, or lack thereof, of global network measures with missing information, but further work is needed to determine how estimates will vary with different data collection methods, network structures, and sampling periods.
WOS:000671690200041
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Wild jackdaws can selectively adjust their social associations while preserving valuable long-term relationships</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-40808-7</url>
<snippet>Influential theories of the evolution of cognition and cooperation posit that tracking information about others allows individuals to adjust their social associations strategically, re-shaping social networks to favour connections between compatible partners. Crucially, to our knowledge, this has yet to be tested experimentally in natural populations, where the need to maintain long-term, fitness-enhancing relationships may limit social plasticity. Using a social-network-manipulation experiment, we show that wild jackdaws (Corvus monedula) learned to favour social associations with compatible group members (individuals that provided greater returns from social foraging interactions), but resultant change in network structure was constrained by the preservation of valuable pre-existing relationships. Our findings provide insights into the cognitive basis of social plasticity and the interplay between individual decision-making and social-network structure.
WOS:001157889300003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Social capital and employee well-being: disentangling intrapersonal and interpersonal selection and influence mechanisms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3917/rfs.493.0613</url>
<snippet>We argue that sociological explanations proposed within the social capital framework to explain individual well-being are incomplete because they do not differentiate between interpersonal influence and selection mechanisms, on the one hand, and cognitive intra-personal processes. on the other. To this end. three theoretical models of the dynamic interaction between interpersonal trust and job satisfaction will be used to derive and empirically test six hypotheses. First, according to influence mechanisms, an individual's job satisfaction can be the result of the number of sociometric trust choices he or she receives (popularity effect) or the level of job satisfaction of those actors he/she trusts (contagion effect). Second, selection mechanisms postulate that a focal actor will be more likely to develop interpersonal trust in colleagues with a high job satisfaction (attractiveness effect) or with similar levels of job satisfaction as the focal actor (homophily effect). Third, according to intrapersonal spillover mechanisms, a high level of job satisfaction can either facilitate the creation of interpersonal trust relationships (satisfaction spillover effect), or individuals initiating a high number of interpersonal trust relationships can exhibit higher levels of satisfaction (trust spillover effect). To simultaneously test these six hypotheses, longitudinal intra-organizational social network data from a Dutch housing company (n = 57) were used. We found a significant contagion effect, but no support for a popularity effect or either selection effect. Moreover, contrary to what we expected, employees with a low level of job satisfaction were significantly more likely to develop trust relationships with others.
WOS:000259277400008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>An Exploration of a Model of Social Networks and Multilateral Negotiations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1571-9979.2009.00230.x</url>
<snippet>Multilateral (many-party) negotiations are much more complex than traditional two-party negotiations. In this article, we explore a model of social network activity, especially clique formation, among parties engaged in multilateral negotiation and the implications that such networks might have on the negotiation process and outcome. Using data collected from 375 subjects participating in a negotiation simulation, our results reveal that, primarily, the negotiator's perspectives of clique formation (coalition building) - both his or her own and the other party's - have unique effects on the integrative, problem-solving approaches used in the process and on the negotiator's satisfaction with outcomes. Secondarily, centrality (manifest as emergent power) has a positive effect on both problem solving and satisfaction. Interestingly, we found that those players who emerged as the most dominant and powerful were not as satisfied (in relative levels) as those who were less powerful.
WOS:000267884200005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Small Worlds and Cultural Polarization</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/0022250X.2010.532261</url>
<snippet>Building on Granovetter's theory of the "strength of weak ties,'' research on "small-world'' networks suggests that bridges between clusters in a social network (long-range ties) promote cultural diffusion, homogeneity, and integration. We show that this macro-level implication of network structure depends on hidden micro-level assumptions. Using a computational model similar to earlier studies, we find that ties between clusters facilitate cultural convergence under the micro-level assumptions of assimilation and attraction to similar others. However, these assumptions also have negative counterparts-differentiation and xenophobia. We found that when these negative possibilities are no longer assumed away, the effect of long-range ties reverses: Even very small amounts of contact between highly clustered communities sharply increased polarization at the population level.
WOS:000286873200006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>"It's like these CHCs don't exist, are they featured anywhere?": Social network analysis of community health committees in a rural and urban setting in Kenya</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0220836</url>
<snippet>Background In Kenya, Community Health Committees (CHC) were established to enhance community participation in health services. Their role is to provide leadership, oversight in delivery of community health services, promote social accountability and mobilize resources for community health. CHCs form social networks with other actors, with whom they exchange health information for decision-making and accountability. This case study aimed to explore the structure of a rural and an urban CHC network and to analyze how health-related information flowed in these networks. Understanding the pathways of information in community settings may provide recommendations for strategies to improve the role and functioning of CHCs. Methods In 2017, we conducted 4 focus group discussions with 27 community discussants and 10 semi-structured interviews with health professionals in a rural area and an urban slum. Using social network analysis, we determined the structure of their social networks and how health related information flowed in these networks. Results Both CHCs were composed of respected persons nominated by their communities. Each social network had 12 actors that represented both community and government institutions. CHCs were not central actors in the exchange of health-related information. Health workers, community health volunteers and local Chiefs in the urban slum often passed information between the different groups of actors, while CHCs hardly did this. Therefore, CHCs had little control over the flow of health-related information. Although CHC members were respected persons who served in multiple roles within their communities, this did not enhance their centrality. It emerged that CHCs were often left out in the flow of health-related information and decision-making, which led to demotivation. Community health volunteers were more involved by other actors such as health managers and non-governmental organizations as a conduit for health-related information. Conclusion Social network analysis demonstrated how CHCs played a peripheral role in the flow of health-related information. Their perception of being left out of the information flow led to demotivation, which hampered their ability to facilitate community participation in community health services; hence challenging effective participation through CHCs.
WOS:000485002500067
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>The Strength of Structural Diversity in Online Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.34133/2021/9831621</url>
<snippet>Understanding the way individuals are interconnected in social networks is of prime significance to predict their collective outcomes. Leveraging a large-scale dataset from a knowledge-sharing website, this paper presents an exploratory investigation of the way to depict structural diversity in directed networks and how it can be utilized to predict one's online social reputation. To capture the structural diversity of an individual, we first consider the number of weakly and strongly connected components in one's contact neighborhood and further take the coexposure network of social neighbors into consideration. We show empirical evidence that the structural diversity of an individual is able to provide valuable insights to predict personal online social reputation, and the inclusion of a coexposure network provides an additional ingredient to achieve that goal. After synthetically controlling several possible confounding factors through matching experiments, structural diversity still plays a nonnegligible role in the prediction of personal online social reputation. Our work constitutes one of the first attempts to empirically study structural diversity in directed networks and has practical implications for a range of domains, such as social influence and collective intelligence studies.
WOS:000658423800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Social media sensors as early signals of influenza outbreaks at scale</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-024-00474-1</url>
<snippet>Detecting early signals of an outbreak in a viral process is challenging due to its exponential nature, yet crucial given the benefits to public health it can provide. If available, the network structure where infection happens can provide rich information about the very early stages of viral outbreaks. For example, more central nodes have been used as social network sensors in biological or informational diffusion processes to detect early contagious outbreaks. We aim to combine both approaches to detect early signals of a biological viral process (influenza-like illness, ILI), using its informational epidemic coverage in public social media. We use a large social media dataset covering three years in a country. We demonstrate that it is possible to use highly central users on social media, more precisely high out-degree users from Twitter, as sensors to detect the early signals of ILI outbreaks in the physical world without monitoring the whole population. We also investigate other behavioral and content features that distinguish those early sensors in social media beyond centrality. While high centrality on Twitter is the most distinctive feature of sensors, they are more likely to talk about local news, language, politics, or government than the rest of the users. Our new approach could detect a better and smaller set of social sensors for epidemic outbreaks and is more operationally efficient and privacy respectful than previous ones, not requiring the collection of vast amounts of data.
WOS:001248745300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Online social integration is associated with reduced mortality risk</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1605554113</url>
<snippet>Social interactions increasingly take place online. Friendships and other offline social ties have been repeatedly associated with human longevity, but online interactions might have different properties. Here, we reference 12 million social media profiles against California Department of Public Health vital records and use longitudinal statistical models to assess whether social media use is associated with longer life. The results show that receiving requests to connect as friends online is associated with reduced mortality but initiating friendships is not. Additionally, online behaviors that indicate face-to-face social activity (like posting photos) are associated with reduced mortality, but online-only behaviors (like sending messages) have a nonlinear relationship, where moderate use is associated with the lowest mortality. These results suggest that online social integration is linked to lower risk for a wide variety of critical health problems. Although this is an associational study, it may be an important step in understanding how, on a global scale, online social networks might be adapted to improve modern populations' social and physical health.
WOS:000388970100046
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Social Isolation in America</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1146/annurev-soc-071312-145646</url>
<snippet>We offer a new measure for social isolation for contemporary society, where opportunities for making connections with others have become ubiquitous. We develop this measure after reviewing previous research on social isolation that we segment into two perspectives. On the one side, isolation has been studied as a negative outcome of processes related to modernization; on the other side, isolation has been studied as a structural position potentially capable of delivering positive returns. Although academic interest in isolation is long-standing, recent years have seen an explosion of research on the topic. We explore the connection between this explosion and new social media and highlight a division within the literature between researchers who see new social media as creating more feelings of isolation and others who think that the jury is still out. In the final section of the article, we offer our novel conceptual framework for studying isolation.
WOS:000348460700007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>A network centrality bias: Central individuals in workplace networks have more supportive coworkers</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2022.12.002</url>
<snippet>Combining the results of two empirical studies, we investigate the role of alters' motivation in explaining change in ego's network position over time. People high in communal motives, who are prone to supportive and altruistic behavior in their interactions with others as a way to gain social acceptance, prefer to establish ties with co-workers occupying central positions in organizational social networks. This effect results in a systematic network centrality bias: The personal network of central individuals (individuals with many incoming ties from colleagues) is more likely to contain more supportive and altruistic people than the personal network of in-dividuals who are less central (individuals with fewer incoming ties). This result opens the door to the possibility that the effects of centrality so frequently documented in empirical studies may be due, at least in part, to characteristics of the alters in an ego's personal community, rather than to egos themselves. Our findings invite further empirical research on how alters' motives affect the returns that people can reap from their personal networks in organizations.
WOS:000923259100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Social networks and risk of delayed hospital arrival after acute stroke</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-09073-5</url>
<snippet>Arriving rapidly to the hospital after a heart attack or stroke is critical for patients to be within time windows for treatment. Prior research in heart attacks has suggested a paradoxical role of the social environment: those who arrive early are surrounded by nonrelatives, while those who arrive late are surrounded by spouses or family members. Here, we used network methods to more deeply examine the influence of social context in stroke. We examined the relationship of personal social networks and arrival time in 175 stroke patients. Our results confirmed the paradox by showing that small and close-knit personal networks of highly familiar contacts, independent of demographic, clinical, and socioeconomic factors, were related to delay. The closed network structure led to constricted information flow in which patients and close confidants, absent outside perspectives, elected to watch-and-wait. Targeting patients with small, close-knit networks may be one strategy to improve response times.
WOS:000461161500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Small world dynamics and the process of knowledge diffusion: The case of the metropolitan area of Greater Santiago de Chile</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>This paper aims to understand some of the mechanisms which dominate the phenomenon of knowledge diffusion in the process that is called 'interactive learning'. We examine how knowledge spreads in a network in which agents have 'face-to-face' learning interactions. We define a social network structured as a graph consisting of agents (vertices) and connections (edges) and situated on a grid which resembles the geographical characteristics of the metropolitan area of Greater Santiago de Chile. The target of this simulation is to test whether knowledge diffuses homogeneously or whether it follows some biased path generating geographical divergence between a core area and a periphery. We also investigate the efficiency of our 'preference' model of agent decision-making and show that this system evolves towards a small-world type network.
WOS:000221935000007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>The Suburbanisation Process: Cultural Approach</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>The Suburbanisation Process: Cultural Approach. Focusing on the process of suburbanisation as a modem urban development, this review article aims to present the culturalist perspective of urban studies. After presenting a brief historical context and the cultural conditions of suburbanisation, the article focuses on three main approaches: social network theory, the relational theory of social and symbolic boundaries, and studies of representations in popular culture. Based on examples of theoretical and empirical studies of suburban development in capitalist cities, the review endeavours to enrich the contemporary agenda of suburban research within a Central European, post-socialist context. Sociologia 2012, Vol. 44 (No. 1: 5-33)
WOS:000300385100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Psychological Well-Being and Brokerage in Friendship Networks of Young Swedes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11205-014-0766-8</url>
<snippet>All ethnic groups have norms and values according to which one is expected to behave. Immigrants in particular have personal networks that simultaneously consist of co-ethnics and friends of a different ethnic background. As a consequence, they may be accustomed to the behavior, norms, and values of their own ethnic group, and also be expected to behave according to those of another ethnic group. This may either lead to ego-gratification and the strengthening and enrichment of their personality, or to feelings of stress and non-acceptance if they cannot behave fully in accordance with the expectations of their friends. This study addresses the association between interethnic open triads in networks (i.e., brokerage) and individual psychological well-being. That is, we examine whether having intra-ethnic and interethnic relationships with friends who are not also friends with each other, is either positively or negatively associated with psychological well-being. Using (network) data from a large sample (N = 2,942; age = 19) of native Swedes and first- and second-generation immigrants from former Yugoslavia and Iran (all born in 1990 and currently living in Sweden), we show that interethnic brokerage is negatively associated with psychological well-being, which implies that the different norms, values and corresponding behaviors that prevail in different ethnic groups to which the ethnic broker is connected may result in internal and external conflicts, to feelings that one is not fully accepted by any of these groups, and ultimately to a lower level of psychological well-being.
WOS:000360078700014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Evolution of non-kin cooperation: social assortment by cooperative phenotype in guppies</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.181493</url>
<snippet>Cooperation among non-kin constitutes a conundrum for evolutionary biology. Theory suggests that non-kin cooperation can evolve if individuals differ consistently in their cooperative phenotypes and assort socially by these, such that cooperative individuals interact predominantly with one another. However, our knowledge of the role of cooperative phenotypes in the social structuring of real-world animal populations is minimal. In this study, we investigated cooperative phenotypes and their link to social structure in wild Trinidadian guppies (Poecilia reticulata). We first investigated whether wild guppies are repeatable in their individual levels of cooperativeness (i.e. have cooperative phenotypes) and found evidence for this in seven out of eight populations, a result which was mostly driven by females. We then examined the social network structure of one of these populations where the expected fitness impact of cooperative contexts is relatively high, and found assortment by cooperativeness, but not by genetic relatedness. By contrast, and in accordance with our expectations, we did not find assortment by cooperativeness in a population where the expected fitness impact of cooperative contexts is lower. Our results provide empirical support for current theory and suggest that assortment by cooperativeness is important for the evolution and persistence of non-kin cooperation in real-world populations.
WOS:000465430600057
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Social Capital and Post-Graduation Destination: International Students in Ireland</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Drawing from social network theory, this study investigates the extent to which bonding and bridging social capital influence the likelihood of staying abroad or returning home after graduation among international students in Ireland. Bonding refers to co-national networks and is measured as the strength of ties and the abundance of resources with co-nationals or family members. Bridging implies crosscutting ties beyond ones co-national network and is measured as contacts with the locals or non-co-nationals. A survey was carried out among Irish university international alumni who graduated between 2014 and 2016. Our main findings suggest: (1) bridging social capital, particularly high-quality and with close bridging ties, are positively associated with the likelihood of staying abroad; (2) human capital, especially field of study and language ability, is positively associated with the likelihood of staying abroad. Policy implications are discussed.
WOS:000574402900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>How gender differences in informal networking result in unequal access to interorganizational R&amp;D projects</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13511610.2024.2380368</url>
<snippet>Women are underrepresented in interorganizational research &amp; development (R&amp;D) projects. This affects the innovativeness of such projects, the representation of female perspectives in the design of innovations and the career opportunities of women. Such projects often emerge from preceding interorganizational R&amp;D projects and are particularly successful when they do so. We argue that instrumental networking in ongoing projects is constitutive for the formation of such follow-up collaborations and, further, that stereotypical gender roles hinder women's participation in instrumental interactions with their current project partners. Hence, we assume that unequal opportunities to participate in follow-up projects can be attributed to women's lesser involvement in instrumental networks. Empirically, we test our argument using data on 2746 directed and weighted personal relationships across 24 interorganizational R&amp;D projects. We show that instrumental interactions are crucial for who initiates follow-up projects with which current partner. Furthermore, we can show that the low participation of women in these activities can be better explained by gender roles than by gender homophily. In doing so, we reveal an important cause of women's under-representation in R&amp;D.
WOS:001276079700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Worth the weight: Conceptualizing and measuring strong versus weak tie homophily</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2021.06.003</url>
<snippet>Homophily, or the tendency for social contact to occur among those who are similar, plays a crucial role in structuring our social networks. Most previous work considers whether homophily shapes the patterns of all social ties, regardless of their frequency of interaction or level of intimacy. As complex network data become increasingly available, however, researchers need to evaluate whether homophily operates differently for ties defined by strong versus weak measures of strength. Here, I take this approach by first defining two variants of homophily: (1) strong tie homophily, or the tendency for ties with high measures of strength to cluster together similar peers, and (2) weak tie homophily, or the tendency for ties with low edge weights to connect sameattribute actors. Then, I apply valued ERGMs to demonstrate the utility of differentiating between the two variants across simulated and observed networks. In most networks, I find that there are observable differences in the magnitude of strong versus weak tie homophily. Additionally, when there are low levels of clustering on the attribute of interest, distinguishing between strong and weak tie homophily can reveal that these processes operate in opposite directions. Since strong and weak ties carry substantively different implications, I argue that differentiating between the two homophily variants has the potential to uncover novel insights on a variety of social phenomena.
WOS:000700623500012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Consensus and polarization in competing complex contagion processes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2019.0196</url>
<snippet>The rate of adoption of new information depends on reinforcement from multiple sources in a way that often cannot be described by simple contagion processes. In such cases, contagion is said to be complex. Complex contagion happens in the diffusion of human behaviours, innovations and knowledge. Based on that evidence, we propose a model that considers multiple, potentially asymmetric and competing contagion processes and analyse its respective population-wide dynamics, bringing together ideas from complex contagion, opinion dynamics, evolutionary game theory and language competition by shifting the focus from individuals to the properties of the diffusing processes. We show that our model spans a dynamical space in which the population exhibits patterns of consensus, dominance, and, importantly, different types of polarization, a more diverse dynamical environment that contrasts with single simple contagion processes. We show how these patterns emerge and how different population structures modify them through a natural development of spatial correlations: structured interactions increase the range of the dominance regime by reducing that of dynamic polarization, tight modular structures can generate structural polarization, depending on the interplay between fundamental properties of the processes and the modularity of the interaction network.
WOS:000473756800015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Reinforced structural holes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2015.04.008</url>
<snippet>Holes in social structure are variably reinforced by the social organization around the hole. The more reinforced the hole, the greater the difficulty in bridging it, but the more likely a successful bridge will carry information novel, and so potentially valuable, to people on the other side. To study how reinforcement varies with access to structural holes, and the achievement associated with access, I propose a measure of access to reinforced structural holes (RSH), and present results predicting achievement in an integrated banker organization and a balkanized supply-chain organization. In both study populations, the people who have access to structural holes also have access to reinforced structural holes, and all measures of access have a statistically significant association with achievement. However, there is no consistent prediction advantage from incorporating reinforcement in measures of access to structural holes. The reinforced-holes measure predicts compensation better or as well as network constraint and betweenness, but is weaker or no better than a count of nonredundant contacts. I do not infer from the results a rank-order of alternative measures so much as substitutability. I expect achievement to be associated with access to structural holes, but I expect the association to vary across alternative measures depending on how achievement is achieved in a specific population. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000358626400014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>The burden of reciprocity: Processes of exclusion and withdrawal from personal networks among low-income families</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0011392112454754</url>
<snippet>Reciprocity has been traditionally treated in sociological and anthropological theory as a force of integration that keeps network members tied together through a complex web of obligations and interdependencies. This article suggests that in the context of poverty it can be a burden and source of relational stress that leads to the demise of social relationships. It is argued that poverty can make it difficult for individuals to maintain relations with others and participate in social support networks because they do not have many resources to share and reciprocate. Recently published ethnographic studies on the social networks of low-income families in the United States form the basis for a micro-level model linking poverty to social fragmentation. By focusing on the suppressive effect of reciprocity, this model identifies two major emergent mechanisms - exclusion and withdrawal - operating in two realms - material and normative - that are conducive to social fragmentation. This article thus promotes our understanding of the ways in which relational dynamics affect low-income families' social well-being and contributes methodologically by laying the groundwork for future empirical research.
WOS:000310461500004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Individuals' power and their social network accuracy: A situated cognition perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2018.01.006</url>
<snippet>Individuals differ in how accurately they perceive their social environment, but research and theory provide conflicting predictions on whether powerful people are more or less accurate than others. Drawing on social network theory and the situated cognition theory of power, we examine the relationship between individuals' formal and informal power and their perceptual accuracy of social network relationships. We propose that individuals' perceptual accuracy is related to: 1) their formal and informal power in the organization; 2) the type of relationship being perceived (positive/negative valence) and its relevance to task and goal completion; and 3) the dependence relationship with the target of perception (i.e., whether the perceiver is dependent on the perceived to get their work done). Predictions were tested using cognitive social structure data collected from a technical call center. Results showed that power was generally linked to increased perceptual accuracy, particularly for the types of relationships most relevant for task and goal completion. We further demonstrated that social network accuracy was related to employees' outcomes, including subsequent transfer, promotion, and exit from the organization. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000432768600013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>Gender homophily in online dyadic and triadic relationships</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-016-0080-6</url>
<snippet>Gender homophily, or the preference for interaction with individuals of the same gender, has been observed in many contexts, especially during childhood and adolescence. In this study we investigate such phenomenon by analyzing the interactions of the similar to 10 million users of Tuenti, a Spanish social networking service popular among teenagers. In dyadic relationships we find evidence of higher gender homophily for women. We also observe a preference of users with more friends to connect to the opposite gender. A particularly marked gender difference emerges in signing up for the social networking service and adding the first friends, and in the interactions by means of wall messages. In these contexts we find evidence of a strong homophily for women, and little or no homophily for men. By examining the gender composition of triangle motifs, we observe a marked tendency of users to group into gender homogeneous clusters, with a particularly high number of male-only triangles. We show that age plays an important role in this context, with a tendency to higher homophily for young teenagers in both dyadic and triadic relationships. Our findings have implications for addressing gender gap issues, understanding adolescent online behavior and technology adoption, and modeling social networks.
WOS:000386969800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Relationality and social interaction</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-4446.2009.01236.x</url>
<snippet>This paper explores Bourdieu's account of a relational social space, and his relative neglect of social interaction within this framework. Bourdieu includes social capital as one of the key relational elements of his social space, but says much less about it than economic or cultural capital, and levels of social capital are rarely measured in his work. Bourdieu is reluctant to focus on the content of social networks as part of his rejection of substantialist thinking. The neglect of substantive networks creates problems for Bourdieu's framework, because many of Bourdieu's core concepts rest upon assumptions about their interactional properties (in particular, the prevalence of homophilous differential association) which are left unexamined. It is argued here that Bourdieu's neglect of the substance of social networks is related to the criticisms that Bourdieu's framework often encounters, and that this neglect bears re-examination, since it is helpful to think of the ways in which differentiated social networks contribute to the development of habitus, help form fields, and so constitute the intersubjective social relations within which sociality, and practice more generally, occur.
WOS:000266242100009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>Early Social Networks Predict Survival in Wild Bottlenose Dolphins</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0047508</url>
<snippet>A fundamental question concerning group-living species is what factors influence the evolution of sociality. Although several studies link adult social bonds to fitness, social patterns and relationships are often formed early in life and are also likely to have fitness consequences, particularly in species with lengthy developmental periods, extensive social learning, and early social bond-formation. In a longitudinal study of bottlenose dolphins (Tursiops sp.), calf social network structure, specifically the metric eigenvector centrality, predicted juvenile survival in males. Additionally, male calves that died post-weaning had stronger ties to juvenile males than surviving male calves, suggesting that juvenile males impose fitness costs on their younger counterparts. Our study indicates that selection is acting on social traits early in life and highlights the need to examine the costs and benefits of social bonds during formative life history stages.
WOS:000309995100123
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>Do social ties foster firms' environmental innovation? The moderating effect of resource bricolage</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09537325.2020.1821876</url>
<snippet>While social ties are central to the field of innovation, the research on the relationship between social ties and environmental innovation is lacking. Based on the resource-based view and social network theory, we construct a research model for identifying the relationships between social ties, resource bricolage, and environmental innovation; we use this to examine the impacts of business, political, and research and development (R&amp;D) ties on firms' levels of radical and incremental eco-innovation, as well as the moderating role of resource bricolage. Multiple regression analysis using survey data from 289 Chinese manufacturing firms is conducted. The results show that political and R&amp;D ties can effectively promote radical eco-innovation, while business and political ties promote incremental eco-innovation. Furthermore, resource bricolage plays a positive moderating role in the relationships between firms' political ties and environmental innovation. These conclusions have certain implications for firms, offering useful insight on how to take full advantage of social ties to acquire various resources and harness resource bricolage strategies to support environmental innovation.
WOS:000569207900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>Places That Bond and Bind: On the Interplay of Space, Places, and Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.17645/si.v10i3.5309</url>
<snippet>Social networks of socially disadvantaged individuals can help them in coping with everyday life and avoiding social exclusion. At the same time, social ties also have the power to bind an individual to their disadvantageous situation, perpetuating the risks of social exclusion. One mechanism through which ties can be established are "foci": extra-network structures around which common interactions occur (e.g., family, workplace, clubs) that usually have spatial anchor points (places) where joint interactions happen. To better understand this interplay of places and networks, we use a methodological novelty that connects a person's everyday places with their ego-centred network (two-mode network). We analyse in depth two cases (elderly women living alone) from a mixed-methods study conducted in rural peripheries in eastern Germany, and we combine data from GPS tracking, qualitative interviews, and egocentric networks. A central finding of our analysis is that tie formation in places is more successful if ego has certain resources (e.g., cultural, financial, or time resources) that allow them to utilise places as foci-hence, ego and places must "match" in their characteristics. Beyond that, the existing foci (and their spatial anchoring as places in everyday life) in which ego is integrated must be considered as structures. Even if a person has enough resources and easy access to places with characteristics that promote contact, this does not automatically mean that they will form ties in such places, as the person's network plays a major role in whether they frequent these places and establish new ties there.
WOS:000861806800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>Dynamic Social Community Detection and Its Applications</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0091431</url>
<snippet>Community structure is one of the most commonly observed features of Online Social Networks (OSNs) in reality. The knowledge of this feature is of great advantage: it not only provides helpful insights into developing more efficient social-aware solutions but also promises a wide range of applications enabled by social and mobile networking, such as routing strategies in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks (MANETs) and worm containment in OSNs. Unfortunately, understanding this structure is very challenging, especially in dynamic social networks where social interactions are evolving rapidly. Our work focuses on the following questions: How can we efficiently identify communities in dynamic social networks? How can we adaptively update the network community structure based on its history instead of recomputing from scratch? To this end, we present Quick Community Adaptation (QCA), an adaptive modularity-based framework for not only discovering but also tracing the evolution of network communities in dynamic OSNs. QCA is very fast and efficient in the sense that it adaptively updates and discovers the new community structure based on its history together with the network changes only. This flexible approach makes QCA an ideal framework applicable for analyzing large-scale dynamic social networks due to its lightweight computing-resource requirement. To illustrate the effectiveness of our framework, we extensively test QCA on both synthesized and real-world social networks including Enron, arXiv e-print citation, and Facebook networks. Finally, we demonstrate the applicability of QCA in real applications: (1) A social-aware message forwarding strategy in MANETs, and (2) worm propagation containment in OSNs. Competitive results in comparison with other methods reveal that social-based techniques employing QCA as a community detection core outperform current available methods.
WOS:000336909100007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Recruitment through Rule Breaking: Establishing Social Ties with Gang Members</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/cico.12272</url>
<snippet>Many contemporary violence prevention programs direct concentrated law enforcement, social service, or educational attention toward individuals engaged in violence, and yet, this population is often avoiding this precise attention. Drawing on 18 months of ethnographic data, this case study asks: How do street outreach workers form social ties with active gang members? This study identifies three key mechanisms of social tie formation that break organizational rules, but account for how new social relations are formed with street savvy gang youth: (1) Network Targeting: identifying, entering, and extending services to the package of preexisting social ties beyond the eligible gang member; (2) Gift Giving: navigating those social ties when transferring out of pocket gifts to the target to elicit trust and demonstrate genuine investment; and (3) Transportation Brokerage: expanding clients' social networks by literally driving them to prosocial influences and activities. Discussion of the value and limitations of each mechanism offers insights to urban sociologists interested in the origins of social ties in disadvantaged communities, as well as policymakers designing social interventions for hard to reach populations.
WOS:000428315200011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>Bots increase exposure to negative and inflammatory content in online social systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1803470115</url>
<snippet>Societies are complex systems, which tend to polarize into subgroups of individuals with dramatically opposite perspectives. This phenomenon is reflected- and often amplified-in online social networks, where, however, humans are no longer the only players and coexist alongside with social bots-that is, software-controlled accounts. Analyzing large-scale social data collected during the Catalan referendum for independence on October 1, 2017, consisting of nearly 4 millions Twitter posts generated by almost 1 million users, we identify the two polarized groups of Independentists and Constitutionalists and quantify the structural and emotional roles played by social bots. We show that bots act from peripheral areas of the social system to target influential humans of both groups, bombarding Independentists with violent contents, increasing their exposure to negative and inflammatory narratives, and exacerbating social conflict online. Our findings stress the importance of developing countermeasures to unmask these forms of automated social manipulation.
WOS:000452124700043
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Multiplexity as a lens to investigate the cultural meanings of interpersonal ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2021.07.002</url>
<snippet>A typical assumption in formal studies of social networks is that interpersonal ties classified under the same label carry the same cultural connotation. As cultural meanings matter for the construction of ties, this premise can be problematic when labels attributed to relationships sustain the simultaneous coexistence of disparate meanings. I argue that the measurement and analysis of multiplexity is a useful tool for testing the validity of this assumption and exploring the cultural meanings of ties using traditional survey data. Employing loglinear models and a datamining technique called 'association rules', I analyze data from the 2004 social networks component of the General Social Survey, which gave subjects the option to classify confidants into multiple relational categories. Contrary to standard assumptions, I find that, subjects report viewing their ties multiplexly a little less than half the time. Familial labels are either perceived as intrinsically meaningful or more broadly as 'friends' and 'advisors.' Spouses are likely to be described as 'friends' only when they are also classified as 'coworkers' or 'group members.' 'Friend' and 'advisor' also display complex layering alongside other labels indicative of flexibility. I discuss implications of my findings for network structure and the cultural meanings of close personal ties.
WOS:000700623500016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Social networkers: Measuring and examining individual differences in propensity to connect with others</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2008.04.003</url>
<snippet>The research examined individual differences in people's propensity to connect with others (PCO). A measure of PCO, with components for making friends (strong ties), making acquaintances (weak ties), and joining others (bridging ties), was developed and tested in two studies involving 144 undergraduates and 197 health-care employees. PCO and its components were significantly positively associated with social network characteristics (including size, betweenness centrality, and brokerage) and indicators of personal adjustment including support received. attainment, well-being, influence, and suggestion-making. PCO had effects beyond those of major personality traits, and PCO components displayed distinctive relationships with work network characteristics. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000260367400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>The Effects of Network Structure on the Emergence of Norms in Adaptive Populations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.18564/jasss.2949</url>
<snippet>The different ways individuals socialize with others affect the conditions under which social norms are able to emerge. In this work an agent-based model of cooperation in a population of adaptive agents is presented. The model has the ability to implement a multitude of network topologies. The agents possess strategies represented by boldness and vengefulness values in the spirit of Axelrod's (1986) norms game. However, unlike in the norms game, the simulations abandon the evolutionary approach and only follow a single-generation of agents who are nevertheless able to adapt their strategies based on changes in their environment. The model is analyzed for potential emergence or collapse of norms under different network and neighborhood configurations as well as different vigilance levels in the agent population. In doing so the model is found able to exhibit interesting emergent behavior suggesting potential for norm establishment even without the use of so-called metanorms. Although the model shows that the success of the norm is dependent on the neighborhood size and the vigilance of the agent population, the likelihood of norm collapse is not monotonically related to decreases in vigilance.
WOS:000369644200014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>Inequality in Access to Social Capital in the Netherlands</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0038038514543294</url>
<snippet>Whereas much research has been done on the benefits of social capital, less is known about the causes of the unequal distribution of social capital in people's networks. This study examines inequalities in access to social capital in terms of the socio-economic resources that are embedded in personal networks. Using data from NELLS, a nationally representative survey of the Dutch population aged 15-45 years, results show that within this age group access to social capital increases with age and educational qualifications, and is lower among women. Residing in a less affluent neighbourhood and scoring lower on a measurement for cognitive abilities are associated with less social capital. Participation in voluntary associations and having an ethnically diverse network are associated with more access to social capital. Surprisingly, when studying differences across national origin groups, we do not find that Turkish immigrants are disadvantaged in access to social capital.
WOS:000354842600008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>Detecting node propensity changes in the dynamic degree corrected stochastic block model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2018.03.004</url>
<snippet>Many applications involve dynamic networks for which a sequence of snapshots of network structure is available over time. Studying the evolution of node propensity over time can be important in exploring and analyzing these networks. In this paper, we propose a multivariate surveillance plan to monitor node propensity in the dynamic degree corrected stochastic block model. The method is flexible enough to detect anomalous nodes that arise from different mechanisms, including individual change, individuals switch, and global change. Experiments on simulated and case study social network data streams demonstrate that our surveillance strategy can efficiently detect node propensity changes in dynamic networks. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000432768600018
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>Generating social capital for bridging ethnic divisions in the Balkans: Case studies of two Bosniak cities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01419870500352397</url>
<snippet>One of the major goals of the international community's intervention into the Balkans is the rebuilding of "viable multiethnic societies". Such societies require support from a population that builds inclusive social capital. I applied social network theory to interethnic relations to help identify the conditions under which minorities could embark on this arduous task in divided, war-torn societies, like Bosnia-Herzegovina. Analysis of data from interviews and participant observation indicate that institutions support positive interethnic relationships when they help people to address practical concerns; allow for individual norms and repeated, mutually dependent interethnic interaction; are rooted in local culture; and are difficult for people to avoid. Nominally mixed urban workplaces and certain types of civic organizations, not advocacy groups or neighbourhoods, meet these criteria. These findings urge scholars working on the role of civil society in rebuilding divided post-conflict societies to look more closely at venues beyond voluntary organizations.
WOS:000234654400004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Is Together Better? Investigating the Relationship Between Network Dynamics and Congregations' Vitality and Sustainability</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13644-022-00496-z</url>
<snippet>Background Although few studies have explored predictors of congregational vitality (i.e., ministry-oriented strengths, not attendance or growth) and sustainability, inter-organizational relationships matter for organizational wellbeing because of their impact on trust, cooperation, and information access. However, investigating the relationship between social capital and congregational vitality and sustainability has not previously been possible due to data limitations. Purpose This article investigates the extent to which brokerage, or bridging together otherwise disconnected congregations, predicts congregational vitality and sustainability in an inter-congregational network of religious congregations from eight counties encompassing and surrounding a major metropolitan area in the southeastern United States. Research on social networks between organizations suggests that brokerage can have positive, negative, and curvilinear relationships with organizational outcomes, and this literature does not provide a clear expectation for how brokerage might relate with congregational vitality and sustainability. Methods OLS regressions are used to predict three forms of vitality and two forms of sustainability using inverse network constraint, a measure of brokerage, as well as a variety of control variables. Statistical significance is estimated through permutation tests, which account for the relationships between congregations. Results Results indicate that brokerage is positively associated with community vitality and that staff/volunteer sustainability is highest for congregations with moderate levels of brokerage. Brokerage does not predict spiritual vitality, relational vitality, or financial sustainability. Conclusions and Implications This article has practical implications for congregations. Bridging together otherwise disconnected congregations can provide a wide range of ideas, resources, and opportunities, and these benefits can help congregations seeking to minister in their communities. In addition, moderate levels of brokerage can provide more diverse information and resources as well as a supportive, trusting, and cooperative environment. This combination of benefits may be helpful for congregations to disclose challenges with and to seek resources related to staff/volunteer sustainability. In addition, this article contributes to the fields of: congregational studies through exploring predictors of congregational vitality and sustainability; sociology of religion through expanding research using social network analysis; inter-organizational networks, whose research on social capital and organizational outcomes is both complicated and conflicting.
WOS:000824933700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Realistic modelling of information spread using peer-to-peer diffusion patterns</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41562-020-00945-1</url>
<snippet>Zhou, Pei et al. develop a more realistic information cascade model that reproduces key structures of real-world diffusion trees in distinct social platforms by combining a peer-to-peer diffusion pattern with a correction for observational bias. In computational social science, epidemic-inspired spread models have been widely used to simulate information diffusion. However, recent empirical studies suggest that simple epidemic-like models typically fail to generate the structure of real-world diffusion trees. Such discrepancy calls for a better understanding of how information spreads from person to person in real-world social networks. Here, we analyse comprehensive diffusion records and associated social networks in three distinct online social platforms. We find that the diffusion probability along a social tie follows a power-law relationship with the numbers of disseminator's followers and receiver's followees. To develop a more realistic model of information diffusion, we incorporate this finding together with a heterogeneous response time into a cascade model. After adjusting for observational bias, the proposed model reproduces key structural features of real-world diffusion trees across the three platforms. Our finding provides a practical approach to designing more realistic generative models of information diffusion.
WOS:000563649500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Don't mention it: Why people don't share job information, when they do, and why it matters</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2011.11.002</url>
<snippet>Network-based job search is especially likely to foster workplace segregation and limit status attainment when information flows through homophilous ties. This paper takes the perspective of information holders and examines how the use of strong versus weak ties - which tend to be homophilous and heterophilous, respectively - differs with characteristics of labour markets in which jobs are located. Using in-depth interviews with entry-level white collar workers I show that information holders with opportunities to mention specific jobs to specific people do so only 27&#37; of the time. Because they hesitate to share information if they are uncertain the information is specifically sought, information flows more commonly to strong ties, whose career goals are more likely to be known. Information is more likely to be shared with weak ties if it concerns occupations for which one may be specifically credentialed, since receiving relevant training serves as signal of interest in such jobs. These finding suggest that the homophily of referrals and their inequality-generating effects may vary across occupations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000302394600004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Granular Mining and Big Data Analytics: Rough Models and Challenges</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40010-018-0578-3</url>
<snippet>Data analytics in granular computing framework is considered for several mining applications, such as in video analysis, bioinformatics and online social networks which have all the characteristics of Big data. The role of granulation, lower approximation and r-f information measure is exhibited. While the lower approximation over a video sequence signifies the object model for unsupervised tracking, it characterizes the probability (relative frequency) of definite regions in ranking miRNAs for normal and cancer classification. For neural learning, the information on definite region is used as the initial knowledge for encoding while generating the networks through evolution. Granules considered are of different sizes and dimensions with fuzzy and crisp boundaries. The tracking method is effective in handling different ambiguous situations, e.g., overlapping objects, newly appeared object(s), multiple objects in different directions and speeds, in unsupervised mode. The ranking algorithm could find only 1&#37; miRNAs to result in significantly higher F-score than the entire set. Fuzzy-rough communities detected over the granular model of social networks are suitable in dealing with overlapping virtual communities in Big data. The knowledge encoding based on fuzzy-rough set provides superior performance than that of rough set. Future directions of research and challenges including the significance of z-numbers in precisiation of granules are stated. The article includes some of the results published elsewhere.
WOS:000536028000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>Advances in biased net theory: definitions, derivations, and estimations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2004.01.005</url>
<snippet>Random and biased net theory, introduced by Rapoport and others in the 1950s, is one of the earliest approaches to the formal modeling of social networks. In this theory, intended as a theory of large-scale networks, ties between nodes derive both from random and non-random events of connection. The non-random connections are postulated to arise through "bias" events that incorporate known or suspected systematic tendencies in tie formation, such as, mutuality or reciprocity, transitivity or closure in triads, and homophily-the overrepresentation of ties between persons who share important socio-demographic attributes like race/ethnicity or level of educational attainment. A key problem for biased net theory has been analytical intractability of the models. Formal derivations require approximation assumptions and model parameters have been difficult to estimate. The accuracy of the derived formulas and the estimated parameters has been difficult to assess. In this paper, we attempt to address long-standing issues in biased net models stemming from their analytical intractability. We first reformulate and clarify the definitions of basic biases. Second, we derive from first principles the triad distribution in a biased net, using two different analytical strategies to check our derivations. Third, we set out a pseudo-likelihood method for parameter estimation of key bias parameters and then check the accuracy of this relatively simple but approximate scheme against the results obtained from the triad distribution derivation. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000221286300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>Unsupervised Scalable Statistical Method for Identifying Influential Users in Online Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-24874-2</url>
<snippet>Billions of users interact intensively every day via Online Social Networks (OSNs) such as Facebook, Twitter, or Google+. This makes OSNs an invaluable source of information, and channel of actuation, for sectors like advertising, marketing, or politics. To get the most of OSNs, analysts need to identify influential users that can be leveraged for promoting products, distributing messages, or improving the image of companies. In this report we propose a new unsupervised method, Massive Unsupervised Outlier Detection (MUOD), based on outliers detection, for providing support in the identification of influential users. MUOD is scalable, and can hence be used in large OSNs. Moreover, it labels the outliers as of shape, magnitude, or amplitude, depending of their features. This allows classifying the outlier users in multiple different classes, which are likely to include different types of influential users. Applying MUOD to a subset of roughly 400 million Google+ users, it has allowed identifying and discriminating automatically sets of outlier users, which present features associated to different definitions of influential users, like capacity to attract engagement, capacity to attract a large number of followers, or high infection capacity.
WOS:000431291500007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Generalized key player problem</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10588-014-9175-4</url>
<snippet>The key player problem (KPP) identifies a set of key nodes that have a central role in a network. In this paper, we propose a generalized KPP (GKPP) that extends existing work on KPP-Pos and KPP-Neg in such a way that it can consider network structure, node attributes, and the characteristics of edges. We also articulate a novel concept called the key player problem for exclusion (KPP-E), which selects a set of nodes to enforce the centrality of a given set of nodes of interest. To solve this problem efficiently, we propose a sequential greedy algorithm that significantly reduces computational complexity. To corroborate the conceptual meaning and effectiveness of the proposed sequential greedy algorithm, we apply GKPP and KPP-E to several real and random networks.
WOS:000350231400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>An efficient counting method for the colored triad census</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2019.04.003</url>
<snippet>The triad census is an important approach to understand local structure in network science, providing comprehensive assessments of the observed relational configurations between triples of actors in a network. However, researchers are often interested in combinations of relational and categorical nodal attributes. In this case, it is desirable to account for the label, or color, of the nodes in the triad census. In this paper, we describe an efficient algorithm for constructing the colored triad census, based, in part, on existing methods for the classic triad census. We evaluate the performance of the algorithm using empirical and simulated data for both undirected and directed graphs. The results of the simulation demonstrate that the proposed algorithm reduces computational time by approximately many-fold over the naive approach. We also apply the colored triad census to the Zachary karate club network dataset. We simultaneously show the efficiency of the algorithm, and a way to conduct a statistical test on the census by forming a null distribution from 1000 realizations of a mixing matrix conditioned graph and comparing the observed colored triad counts to the expected. From this, we demonstrate the method's utility in our discussion of results about homophily, heterophily, and bridging, simultaneously gained via the colored triad census. In sum, the proposed algorithm for the colored triad census brings novel utility to social network analysis in an efficient package.
WOS:000472813200011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="52">
<title>Brain Sensitivity to Exclusion is Associated with Core Network Closure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-33624-3</url>
<snippet>Humans are driven to pursue and preserve social relationships, and these motivations are reinforced through biological systems. In particular, individual differences in the tuning of biological systems that respond to social threats may motivate individuals to seek out differently structured social environments. Drawing on a sample of adolescent males who underwent fMRI brain imaging (n = 74) and contributed Facebook data, we examined whether biological responses to a common scenariobeing excluded from an activity with peers -was associated with their social network structure. We find that neural responses during social exclusion in a priori hypothesized "social pain" regions of the brain (dACC, AI, subACC) are associated with the density and transitivity of core friendship networks. These findings suggest that neural reactivity to exclusion may be one factor that underlies network "safety". More broadly, the study shows the potential of linking social cognitive tendencies to social structural properties.
WOS:000448727600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="53">
<title>Occupations and their impact on the spreading of COVID-19 in urban communities</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-18392-5</url>
<snippet>The current pandemic has disproportionally affected the workforce. To improve our understanding of the role that occupations play in the transmission of COVID-19, we analyse real-world network data that were collected in Bucharest between August 1st and October 31st 2020. The data record sex, age, and occupation of 6895 patients and the 13,272 people they have interacted with, thus providing a social network from an urban setting through which COVID-19 has spread. Quite remarkably, we find that medical occupations have no significant effect on the spread of the virus. Instead, we find common transmission chains to start with infected individuals who hold jobs in the private sector and are connected with non-active alters, such as spouses, siblings, or elderly relatives. We use relational hyperevent models to assess the most likely homophily and network effects in the community transmission. We detect homophily with respect to age and anti-homophily with respect to sex and employability. We note that, although additional data would be welcomed to perform more in-depth network analyses, our findings may help public authorities better target under-performing vaccination campaigns.
WOS:000841942700035
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="54">
<title>Counting on kin: The satisfaction of migrants with their social networks in Germany</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijintrel.2019.05.001</url>
<snippet>Migrants are often considered deprived at least in terms of income, housing and health. However, social networks with their support potential also differ between locals and migrants. Compared to locals, migrants are supposed to have strong family and co-ethnic ties more often. Therefore, in the scientific literature, it is disputed whether migrants' social networks are insufficient. Moreover, how network structure is related to satisfaction with bonds is nearly unobserved. However, satisfaction can be interpreted as an expression for social condition and, therefore, as an indicator of social inequality. Hence, we examine the social networks of Germans and seven migrant groups using the German Socio-Economic Panel (2006 and 2011). Precisely, we investigated how the network of seven migrant groups and Germans are related to satisfaction with their social networks. Our results revealed that the extent of bonding capital promotes support if required. However, apart from origin, network structure affects expectations of kin and non-kin support, which has unequal effects on satisfaction in relationships with closely linked persons. Non-kin helpers seemed to be experienced as substitutes for family support. In contrast to the networks of Germans, the perceived sufficiency of migrant networks is not negatively affected by bonding capital.
WOS:000473839300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="55">
<title>Estimating the causal effect of social capital: A review of recent research</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1146/annurev.soc.32.061604.123150</url>
<snippet>Although there is a large literature on social capital, empirical estimates of the effect of social capital may be biased because of social homophily, the tendency of similar people to become friends with each other. Despite the methodological difficulties, a recent literature has emerged across several different disciplines that tries to estimate the causal effect of social capital. This paper reviews this recent empirical literature on social capital, paying close attention to the statistical and theoretical assumptions involved. Overall, there is evidence that genuine progress has been made in estimating the effect of social capital. The reviewed articles should provide useful examples for future research.
WOS:000240319100004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="56">
<title>The Emergence and Stability of Groups in Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2019.10.008</url>
<snippet>An important puzzle in social network research is to explain how macro-level structures emerge from micro-level network processes. Explaining the emergence and stability of structural groups in social networks is particularly difficult for two reasons. First, because groups are characterized both by high connectedness within (group cohesion) and lack of connectedness between them (group boundaries). Second, because a large number of theoretical micro-level network processes contribute to their emergence. We argue that traditional social network theories that are concerned with the evolution of positive relations (forces of attraction) are not sufficient to explain the emergence of groups because they lack mechanisms explaining the emergence of group boundaries. Models that additionally account for the evolution of negative ties (forces of repulsion) may be better suited to explain the emergence and stability of groups. We build a theoretical model and illustrate its usefulness by fitting stochastic actor-oriented models (SAOMs) to empirical data of co-evolving networks of friendship and dislike among 479 secondary-school students. The SAOMs include a number of newly developed effects expressing the co-evolution between positive and negative ties. We then simulate networks from the estimated models to explore the micro-macro link. We find that a model that considers forces of attraction and repulsion simultaneously is better at explaining groups in social networks. In the long run, however, the empirically informed simulations generate networks that are too stylized to be realistic, raising further questions about model degeneracy and time heterogeneity of group processes.
WOS:000501619700011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="57">
<title>An agent-based random-utility-maximization model to generate social networks with transitivity in geographic space</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2013.05.002</url>
<snippet>Stochastic actor-based approaches receive increasing interest in the generation of social networks for simulation in time and space. Existing models however cannot be readily integrated in agent-based models that assume random-utility-maximizing behavior of agents. We propose an agent-based model to generate social networks explicitly in geographic space which is formulated in the random-utility-maximizing (RUM) framework. The proposed model consists of a friendship formation mechanism and a component to simulate social encounters in a population. We show how transitivity can be incorporated in both components and how the model can be estimated based on data of personal networks using likelihood estimation. In an application to the Swiss context, we demonstrate the estimation and ability of the model to reproduce relevant characteristics of networks, such as geographic proximity, attribute similarity (homophily), size of personal networks (degree distribution) and clustering (transitivity). We conclude that the proposed social-network model fits seamlessly in existing large-scale micro-simulation systems which assume RUM behavior of agents. 
WOS:000322692600016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="58">
<title>The Effect of Gossip on Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cplx.20334</url>
<snippet>In this article, we develop a simple model for the effect of gossip spread on social network structure. We define gossip as information passed between two individuals A and B about a third individual C which affects the strengths of all three relationships: it strengthens A-B and weakens both B-C and A-C. We find, in both an analytic derivation and model simulations, that if gossip does not spread beyond simple triads, it destroys them but if gossip propagates through large dense clusters, it strengthens them. Additionally, our simulations show that the effect of gossip on network metrics (clustering coefficient, average-path-length, and sum-of-strengths) varies with network structure and average-node-degree. (C) 2010 Wiley Periodicals, Inc. Complexity 16: 39-47, 2011
WOS:000288607500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="59">
<title>Friendship by assignment? From formal interdependence to informal relations in organizations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0018726718789479</url>
<snippet>We offer the first field experiment showing how job assignments create social ties at work and influence their persistence. Pairs of managers were assigned at random to project teams. We show that once those pairs work together and become interdependent, they are more likely to create informal relationships (friendships and advice ties). Interdependence also increases the persistence of the informal ties that existed prior to team assignments; the magnitude of this effect decreases with tie strength. As organizations extend their use of teamwork, they also create and maintain social networks across functional and geographic boundaries. Thus, transitory project teams forge an enduring organizational legacy.
WOS:000465910800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="60">
<title>Embedded Distress: Social Integration, Gender, and Adolescent Depression</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/sf/soac034</url>
<snippet>In adolescence, teens manage close friendships while simultaneously evaluating their social position in the larger peer context. Conceptualizing distinct local and global network structures clarifies how social integration relates to mental wellbeing. Examining local cohesion and global embeddedness in the context of key factors related to mental health, such as gender and friends' depression, can further distinguish when the structure and content of social integration relate to higher and lower depressive levels. Analyses using survey data from PROSPER (n = 27,091, grades 9-12) indicate global embeddedness is generally protective, but for girls, greater global embeddedness when friends are more depressive is associated with increased depressive symptoms. For girls, greater local cohesion reduces associations between more depressive friends and increased depressive levels, while for boys, both local cohesion and friends' depression are largely irrelevant. Results indicate the importance of considering both local and global network integration in tandem with gender and friends' depression to understand how social integration relates to mental health.
WOS:000785676800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="61">
<title>Bringing Managers Back In: Managerial Influences on Workplace Inequality</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0003122411420814</url>
<snippet>While great progress has been made in documenting that organizational practices affect workplace inequality, little is known about how managers in particular may shape the careers of the employees below them. Using unique longitudinal personnel data on managers and their subordinates, this study identifies and tests for evidence of three distinct mechanisms by which managers potentially influence the assessment of employee performance in the workplace: (1) social network influence between employees' current and former managers; (2) manager-manager (horizontal) homophily; and (3) manager-employee (vertical) homophily. I find evidence of the independent effects of all three mechanisms of managerial influence on the outcome of disagreement in the performance evaluation ratings of the same worker between former and current managers. In particular, my results stress that both managerial network influence and horizontal homophily affect the process of employee performance assessments, over and above the well-studied vertical homophily mechanism. I conclude by discussing the theoretical implications of these findings for future research regarding the interactional aspects of workplace inequality within contemporary organizations.
WOS:000295334500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="62">
<title>Measuring web ecology by Facebook, Twitter, blogs and online news: 2012 general election in South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11135-014-0016-9</url>
<snippet>This study aimed to provide an empirical and analytical account of online information flow and web ecology in four platforms around the 2012 general election in South Korea. The study quantitatively examined the interrelationship of web ecology among relevant platforms-including online news, blogs, Twitter and Facebook-during election campaigns. In order to quantify the current political situations, this study employed network analysis and the model fitting method with co-occurrence web visibility data of political parties and their leaders in four platforms. The findings demonstrated to what extent web ecologies on four different online platforms during the given election reflect the country's political situation. Comparing network centralizations across platforms, results showed that online news was the least biased media and Twitter was the most biased with the highest centralization scores. Although both the ruling party and the major opposition party-including the leaders of those two parties-had higher degree centrality scores than minor parties and their leaders in all platforms, some distinct features were observed in Twitter and Facebook due to their attributes. In addition, regressions and their residuals confirmed that web ecologies in four platforms, in terms of degree centrality, had been linearly expanded over time and showed their individual characteristics.
WOS:000352509200017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="63">
<title>Intergenerational Closure and Academic Achievement in High School: A New Evaluation of Coleman's Conjecture</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/003804070908200304</url>
<snippet>This article reexamines the conjecture of James S. Coleman that intergenerational social closure promotes student achievement in high schools, analyzing the best national data on academic achievement and social networks: the 2002 and 2004 waves of the Education Longitudinal Study. The results show that within the Catholic school sector, schools that are characterized by dense parental networks have substantially higher average student achievement. This association can be reduced but not eliminated by conditioning on available measures of student network structure and standard measures of family background. In contrast, in the public school sector, a similarly strong bivariate association between dense parental networks and student achievement can be attributed almost entirely to these basic conditioning variables. These results represent, at best, a mixed verdict for Coleman's predictions. Intergenerational closure in its currently observed form does not increase achievement in public schools, suggesting that parental monitoring of discipline does not outweigh some of the costs of parental closure. However, intergenerational closure may increase achievement in Catholic schools to a modest degree because Catholic schools are affiliated with religious communities that have appropriable norms.
WOS:000269035800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="64">
<title>Patterns of support and conflict relationships in personal networks and perceived stress</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0011392120948926</url>
<snippet>This article investigates the association between personal networks and stress, both positively through support and negatively through conflict. In a representative sample of 755 individuals residing in Switzerland, each individual was asked to name people in their lives who they perceived as very important, as well as to report their mutual support and conflict interactions. First, the article develops and investigates a typology with five relational patterns based on indicators of emotional support and conflict relationships in personal networks. These patterns are the following:bonding social capital,bridging social capital,ego-centered conflict,overload, andambivalent. Second, it explores the association of these patterns with stress levels that are perceived in various life domains. Results show that individuals involved in relationships that were predominantly supportive had lower levels of stress, whereas individuals experiencing relationships characterized by conflict, or an imbalance in support by giving more than receiving, had higher levels of stress. Finally, ambivalent relationships in which support and conflict were equally present were associated with an intermediate level of stress. These results show the importance of considering support and conflict relationships together in personal network structures.
WOS:000570340900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="65">
<title>Age integration in the social convoys of young and late midlife adults</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.alcr.2023.100540</url>
<snippet>Homophily on the basis of age is a notable characteristic of social convoys across the life course. Ties to older and younger persons, therefore, are both unusual and potentially provide unique social support resources. This study examined relationships with older, younger, and same-aged non-kin ties among young and late midlife adults. Data came from the University of California Berkeley Social Networks Study (UCNets), a sample of 485 people aged 21-30 and 674 people aged 50-70. A majority of non-kin ties were to people whose age was within 5 years of the participant's own age, although the majority was much larger for young adults (81 &#37;) than late midlife adults (52 &#37;). Younger and older ties often came from different social settings (school, work, religious organi-zations, and neighborhoods) than same-aged ties, and there were also some cohort differences in the social settings that produced younger, older, and same-aged ties. Younger and older ties also provided different forms of social support than did ties to same-aged persons. Again, the functions of younger and older ties varied by cohort. Implications for life course studies are discussed.
WOS:000956939800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="66">
<title>Verification in Referral-Based Crowdsourcing</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0045924</url>
<snippet>Online social networks offer unprecedented potential for rallying a large number of people to accomplish a given task. Here we focus on information gathering tasks where rare information is sought through "referral-based crowdsourcing'': the information request is propagated recursively through invitations among members of a social network. Whereas previous work analyzed incentives for the referral process in a setting with only correct reports, misreporting is known to be both pervasive in crowdsourcing applications, and difficult/costly to filter out. A motivating example for our work is the DARPA Red Balloon Challenge where the level of misreporting was very high. In order to undertake a formal study of verification, we introduce a model where agents can exert costly effort to perform verification and false reports can be penalized. This is the first model of verification and it provides many directions for future research, which we point out. Our main theoretical result is the compensation scheme that minimizes the cost of retrieving the correct answer. Notably, this optimal compensation scheme coincides with the winning strategy of the Red Balloon Challenge.
WOS:000312385200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="67">
<title>A Communication Multiplexity Approach to Social Capital: On- and Offline Communication and Self-Esteem</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0894439314552803</url>
<snippet>This study explores the mechanisms by which online social information seeking (i.e., monitoring Facebook friends) relates to social capital. Based on the extant literature, we propose a theoretical framework that includes communication activities across different channels operationalized as offline participation, network structure on social network site operationalized as the number of actual online friends and network diversity, and self-esteem. Results from an online survey (N = 223) found a moderated mediation model in which participation in offline social activities mediated the relationship between social information seeking and self-reported bonding social capital, and self-esteem moderated this mediation. In addition, participation in offline social activities provided an additional channel to accessing bridging social capital. These results provide a theoretical framework for and suggest an approach of communication multiplexity to future research.
WOS:000357749200005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="68">
<title>Does it take &lt;i&gt;three&lt;/i&gt; to dance the Tango? Organizational design, triadic structures and boundary spanning across subunits</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2019.04.002</url>
<snippet>In this paper, we investigate the processes of boundary spanning across subunits within organizational networks. We hypothesize that patterns of advice across organizational subunits are explained by different triadic mechanisms depending on the organizational design of the intra-organizational network. In organizational networks characterized by limited hierarchical differentiation among members and horizontal coordination, we found triadic cyclic closure to be positively associated to boundary spanning across subunits; but when the network reflects an organizational structure with formal hierarchical differentiation among members, then we found triadic transitive closure to be associated to boundary spanning across subunits. We test these predictions in two empirical studies consisting of two organizational networks that differ from each other in organizational design. We adopt a Bayesian approach for exponential random graph models specifically designed for the statistical analysis of interpersonal relationships within and across subgroups or subunits. We suggest that the effects of informal, triadic network configurations on boundary spanning are contingent on formal organizational design.
WOS:000487171000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="69">
<title>Stability and dynamics of communities on online question-answer sites</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2018.12.004</url>
<snippet>Social networks are present in our everyday lives, not just in face to face communication, but also when we communicate through the Internet. The latter leaves massive traces of data and thereby opens opportunities to acquire a better understanding of social communities in general. In this work, we are particularly interested in the patterns of volunteer efforts within the communities. To that end, we examine the community structure of several large online question-answer sites and how they evolve over time. To describe the user interaction patterns concisely, we employ the hyperbolic community model. This statistical model allows for a summary of each community in each time step by means of intuitive parameters that reflect the connectivity pattern within the network. Our study of the temporal evolution of these parameters reveals an important characteristic: In contrast to what has been observed earlier in the analyses of growth behaviour of online communities, we observe that the user activity within a community is constant with respect to its size throughout its lifetime. Furthermore, the structural organisation of different communities across different question-answer sites seems to follow a common scheme: There is a small group of users who is responsible for the majority of the social interactions.
WOS:000472813200005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="70">
<title>Messy Arrangements? A Social Networks Perspective on Migrant Labor Brokerage: The Case of Ukrainian Migration to Poland</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.26412/psr220.03</url>
<snippet>This article draws on two studies conducted between 2016 and 2018 on the nature of labor migration from Ukraine to Poland. Using quantitative and qualitative data, it analyses the relationship between social networks and employment agencies. Building on research into migration infrastructure, we question the dichotomy-which also appears in migrants' narratives-between migrant social networks and labor brokers, and offer evidence of overlap and interdependence between the two. Exploring various aspects of labor migration, we look at the role played by the social networks of the actors (both the migrants and the intermediaries) in enhancing migration infrastructure. We show how migrants use their social capital in regard to labor brokers and how the latter, rather than replacing networks, mobilize their network resources and experience to create a trusted transnational service.
WOS:000922064400003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="71">
<title>Markets or networks: Households' choice of financial intermediary in Western China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2012.08.003</url>
<snippet>We argue that households' choice of financial intermediary is conditioned by households' social network structures and socioeconomic status. Analyses show that households' social network size and network composition affect their choices by limiting the quality and quantity of information, resources, and social influence one can access through social ties. Moreover, we find that high-SES families favor formal intermediaries due not only to their richer financial knowledge, higher affordability, and greater capacity to repay loans, but also to their high demands and special types of financial needs that can hardly be satisfied by embedded resources. 
WOS:000313304100029
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="72">
<title>Should I use my 'weak' social capital or 'strong' &lt;i&gt;guanxi&lt;/i&gt;? Reviewing and critiquing two theories in the context of Western-Chinese migration</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1440783320925152</url>
<snippet>Social network dynamics are complex in the context of Chinese overseas migration because of the unique dynamics of guanxi, which are distinctly different from 'Western' social capital. The few migration studies comparing guanxi and social capital suggest that the former largely consists 'strong ties', while the latter is comprised of 'weak ties'. However, most apply only a cursory comparison of one network facet. We review core literature in the two fields to contrast what each says about network norms, structures and practices. We find that: (i) guanxi is characterised by dynamics of 'face' and renqing; (ii) guanxi has core and peripheral aspects that grant it bonding and bridging qualities; (iii) weak ties in social capital networks are more beneficial for acquiring non-redundant resources, and for joining civic/voluntary associations; (iv) while strong, face-based guanxi ties better mobilise valuable resources, these ties are rarely transformed into social capital.
WOS:000538920000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="73">
<title>Risk issue adoption in an online social movement field</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2019.1620823</url>
<snippet>This article extends the field conceptualisation of social change and innovation adoption, which hinges upon the strategic capacities of actors, to the online environment. We focus on a key aspect of social movement organisations (SMOs), competition for members, resources and attention over an environmental risk issue. The incorporation of network theory enables us to map how the structural position of actors in the field is associated with their actions- for example, their response to an exogenous shock such as a new threat to the environment. We analyse how actors in the online environmental movement respond to the emergence of nanoscience and technology (NST) as a risk issue, and test the field theory hypothesis that dominated actors are more likely to adopt this issue in the early stages of emergence. Our findings challenge field theory orthodoxy and suggest that whilst challengers innovate, dominants co-opt by adopting the issue in a second stage. Finally, we examine why the notion that NST entails significant environmental and health risks was not propelled into wider public consciousness.
WOS:000474288700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="74">
<title>Nonreligious Group Factors Versus Religious Belief in the Prediction of Prosociality</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11205-014-0700-0</url>
<snippet>Previous research has suggested that religious belief is associated with a range of prosocial behaviors such as social embeddedness and generosity. However, this literature has often conflated belief in God with group involvement and failed to control for demographic and social network effects. Rather than assessing prosociality by comparing religious group members with the unaffiliated, the present study also includes secular/nonreligious group members. Multiple regression analyses controlling for confounds diminishes many of the apparent differences between religious and nonreligious individuals. Belief in God itself accounts for approximately 1-2 &#37; of the variance in social embeddedness domains and &lt; 1 &#37; of the variance in the domains of outside-group charity and community volunteering. Belief in God is associated with homophily and parochial behavior such as within-group charitable donations and constrained contact with different others. These findings indicate that prosocial benefits are more related to general group membership equally available to religious and secular group members alike than they are to specifically religious content. Religious beliefs are related to within-group prosociality as well as homophily and parochialism directed to those outside the group.
WOS:000353792100005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="75">
<title>Tangled Roots: Personal Networks and the Participation of Individuals in an Anti-environmentalism Countermovement</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0731121420908886</url>
<snippet>We focus on the personal networks of members of an anti-environmentalism countermovement in a small town in Canada (Port Alberni, B.C.) that mobilized against the environmental movement. Drawing primarily from social survey data, we investigate the effects of network-based mobilization processes, and contending-movement ties (ties to the environmental movement), on level of participation in the countermovement. We add to the literature on networks and social movements, and movement-countermovement dynamics by 1) comparing network processes amongst a counter movement with those amongst a corresponding social movement, and 2) comparing personal network structures and mobilization processes between countermovement members and the general public. We find a similar pattern of network-based micromobilization processes amongst movement and countermovement participant networks. We find both similarities, and key differences between the counter movement and the general public in terms of activism and social network ties. Theoretical predictions have suggested that individuals who have ties to opposing groups will moderate their participation in a social movement. However, in this study of a community countermovement organization in a small town in Canada that mobilized against the provincial environmental movement we find that the number of contending movement ties (the range of ties to environmental organizations) held by individuals in the countermovement has a significant positive association with countermovement activism, and is the strongest statistical predictor of countermovement activism. Drawing upon both theory and substantive information we discuss the implications of this novel finding.
WOS:000536524300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="76">
<title>NET AND JET The Internet use, travel and social networks of Chinese Canadian entrepreneurs</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13691180902858080</url>
<snippet>How does the connectivity afforded by new communication and transportation technologies affect entrepreneurs' geographic and social closeness to each other? Using qualitative and quantitative evidence we analyse how Chinese Canadian entrepreneurs combine the Internet and airplane travel in their business activities. Our results show that the use of new communication and transportation technologies are positively related to the creation and maintenance of 'glocalized' networks, a function of both local embeddedness and global outreach. We find that online interaction cannot replace face-to-face interaction; travel abroad is crucial for adding a human touch to glocalized networks. Moreover, while technologies help to liberate communication from being local, Internet use and travel have limited impact on the ethnic diversity of the entrepreneurs' social networks.
WOS:000207871100005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="77">
<title>The intervening role of social integration in the effect of education on subjective mental health</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.rssm.2023.100786</url>
<snippet>This paper contributes to the literature examining the interplay of education, social integration, and mental health. Based on social network theories, we argue that social integration plays a role in explaining the link between education and mental health. Using data from the German Panel Study Labour Market and Social Security (PASS) (observation period: 2006/2007-2018), our sample comprises 16,870 individuals. We use panel regression models to analyze the association between education and the probability of reporting at least good mental health. Based on mediation analysis techniques, we investigate the mediating role of strong and weak ties in this relationship. Results show that overall social integration, the number of close friends and relatives, and memberships in voluntary associations partly explain the link between education and mental health.
WOS:001001400700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="78">
<title>Experientially simulated others: finding social support for mental health in digital games</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2024.2396632</url>
<snippet>People with mental illness struggle to find connection and community due to a combination of stigma, social isolation, and adverse social experiences. Digital games, as an immersive and interactive media, can convey aspects of mental health experiences in thoughtful ways. I considered how players connect with characters in digital games about mental health. Combining social network theories and science and technology studies, this qualitative grounded theory study of 48 people who play video games and experience mental illness found that players perceive and form bonds with characters as experientially similar to themselves. Players engaged with different commercially-available games about mental health and felt less alone in their own experiences, identified new coping strategies, and envisioned alternate self-narratives. I put forward a concept, experientially simulated others, to define the specific ways that digital games' interactivity and immersivity enhance the impacts of connecting with shared mental health experiences.
WOS:001299341700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="79">
<title>People are scarier than ghosts? Workplace haters and knowledge sharing</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ssqu.13278</url>
<snippet>Objective.In the workplace, colleague relationship deeply affects employees' work attitude and behavior, but it is rarely taken seriously. Based on the cognitive-affective personality system theory and social network theory, this study examined the influence of three common workplace haters (negative gossiper, two-faced person, and loafer) on employee well-being and knowledge sharing and explores the moderating effect of organizational social capital. Method.The study used longitudinal design, three-wave, and 409 valid supervisor-employee pairs (233 direct supervisors and 409 employees) from 10 companies in Taiwan to test these hypothetical relationships. Results. The findings of this study showed that: (1) workplace haters negatively affects employee well-being; (2) employee well-being positively affects knowledge sharing; (3) employee well-being mediates the relationship between workplace haters and knowledge sharing; and (4) organizational social capital moderates the relationship between workplace haters and employee well-being. Conclusion. The study has important contributions to the literature on workplace haters, coworker interaction, and social capital. Implications for behavioral researchers and human resource managers are discussed.
WOS:000972345600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="80">
<title>The tie effect on information dissemination: the spread of a commercial rumor in Hong Kong</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0378-8733(01)00050-8</url>
<snippet>The ability to acquire information has been considered a crucial factor facilitating instrumental actions, such as job search and organizational innovation. Previous social network studies tend to treat the characteristics of social ties through which information is acquired as causes that may affect instrumental outcomes. However, little research has directly examined the spread of information via social ties and the tie effect on information dissemination. Using telephone survey data collected after the outbreak of an extensive commercial rumor in Hong Kong, the present paper investigates the characteristics of social ties through which the information is spread and the tie effect on information dissemination. Results show that while mass media, particularly television, serves as a major channel of information flow, social ties are also widely used. Individuals tend to share information with strong ties, or people with whom they perceive to have good relations. However, information transmitted via kin ties tends to arrive at the respondent faster than via nonkin ties or other communication channels. Implications of the findings are discussed. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000174169100003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="81">
<title>Categorical closure: Transitivity and identities in longitudinal networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2024.06.004</url>
<snippet>This research examines whether categorical closure - an increased tendency for closure in homogeneous triads - matters for tie formation and tie persistence. We utilized 2019-2020 panel data on students' networks at three law schools and employed separable temporal exponential random graph models to examine whether closed triads with shared identities were more likely to form and to persist over time. We also investigated whether closed triads based on shared organizational assignments were associated with lower likelihoods of tie formation and tie persistence over time. Results supported the notion that law students were more likely to form homogeneous closed triads based on shared categories, particularly family background, gender, and race, while closed triads based on organizational assignments were less likely. Closed triads tended to persist over time, but there was some support for the notion that homogeneous closed triads based on family background, college rank, and sexuality were more durable. This study highlights categorical closure as an additional network mechanism giving rise to homogenous groups.
WOS:001264836000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="82">
<title>The equivalence of two rational expectations equilibrium economies with different approaches to processing neighbors' information</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mathsocsci.2020.11.003</url>
<snippet>We consider a finite-agent Hellwig (1980) economy with an extension to allow traders to observe their neighbors' signals in an exogenously given social network. There are two potential approaches for traders to process observed signals: directly infer information about the fundamentals from the complete collection of observed signals, or indirectly from an average of observed signals. The two approaches lead to different information sets for traders. In this study, we investigate whether the two economies corresponding to the two approaches are equivalent in the sense that they have the same market equilibrium. For general network and signal structures, we present a necessary and sufficient condition for the equivalence, revealing that the two finite-agent economies are not equivalent in general unless the network structure and signal structure coordinate well. When traders have homogeneous preferences and the signal structure takes the classical form in the literature, we find that the two finite-agent economies are equivalent for regular graphs, but not for chain and star graphs. Finally, for the classical signal structure, we show that the two large economies, defined as the limit of a sequence of replica finite-agent economies, are equivalent for any network structure. (C) 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000610412600008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="83">
<title>Social learning and partisan bias in the interpretation of climate trends</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1722664115</url>
<snippet>Vital scientific communications are frequently misinterpreted by the lay public as a result of motivated reasoning, where people misconstrue data to fit their political and psychological biases. In the case of climate change, some people have been found to systematically misinterpret climate data in ways that conflict with the intended message of climate scientists. While prior studies have attempted to reduce motivated reasoning through bipartisan communication networks, these networks have also been found to exacerbate bias. Popular theories hold that bipartisan networks amplify bias by exposing people to opposing beliefs. These theories are in tension with collective intelligence research, which shows that exchanging beliefs in social networks can facilitate social learning, thereby improving individual and group judgments. However, prior experiments in collective intelligence have relied almost exclusively on neutral questions that do not engage motivated reasoning. Using Amazon's Mechanical Turk, we conducted an online experiment to test how bipartisan social networks can influence subjects' interpretation of climate communications from NASA. Here, we show that exposure to opposing beliefs in structured bipartisan social networks substantially improved the accuracy of judgments among both conservatives and liberals, eliminating belief polarization. However, we also find that social learning can be reduced, and belief polarization maintained, as a result of partisan priming. We find that increasing the salience of partisanship during communication, both through exposure to the logos of political parties and through exposure to the political identities of network peers, can significantly reduce social learning.
WOS:000445545200045
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="84">
<title>Quantifying the Role of Homophily in Human Cooperation Using Multiplex Evolutionary Game Theory</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0140646</url>
<snippet>Nature shows as human beings live and grow inside social structures. This assumption allows us to explain and explore how it may shape most of our behaviours and choices, and why we are not just blindly driven by instincts: our decisions are based on more complex cognitive reasons, based on our connectedness on different spaces. Thus, human cooperation emerges from this complex nature of social network. Our paper, focusing on the evolutionary dynamics, is intended to explore how and why it happens, and what kind of impact is caused by homophily among people. We investigate the evolution of human cooperation using evolutionary game theory on multiplex. Multiplexity, as an extra dimension of analysis, allows us to unveil the hidden dynamics and observe non-trivial patterns within a population across network layers. More importantly, we find a striking role of homophily, as the higher the homophily between individuals, the quicker is the convergence towards cooperation in the social dilemma. The simulation results, conducted both macroscopically and microscopically across the network layers in the multiplex, show quantitatively the role of homophily in human cooperation.
WOS:000363309200026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="85">
<title>A general framework to link theory and empirics in opinion formation models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-09468-3</url>
<snippet>We introduce a minimal opinion formation model that is quite flexible and can reproduce a wide variety of the existing micro-influence assumptions and models. The model can be easily calibrated on real data, upon which it imposes only a few requirements. From this perspective, our model can be considered as a bridge, connecting theoretical studies on opinion formation models and empirical research on social dynamics. We investigate the model analytically by using mean-field approximation and numerically via Monte Carlo simulations. Our analysis is exemplified by recently reported empirical data drawn from an online social network. We demonstrate that the model calibrated on these data may reproduce fragmented and polarizing social systems. Furthermore, we manage to generate an artificial society that features properties quantitatively and qualitatively similar to those observed empirically at the macro scale. This ability became possible after we had advanced the model with two important communication features: selectivity and personalization algorithms.
WOS:000777214100044
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="86">
<title>The sensitivity of respondent-driven sampling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-985X.2011.00711.x</url>
<snippet>. Researchers in many scientific fields make inferences from individuals to larger groups. For many groups, however, there is no list of members from which to draw a random sample. Respondent-driven sampling (RDS) is a relatively new sampling methodology that circumvents this difficulty by using the social networks of the groups under study. The RDS method has been shown to provide unbiased estimates of population proportions given certain conditions. The method is now widely used in human immunodeficiency virus related studies among high risk populations globally. We test the RDS methodology by simulating RDS studies on the social networks of a large Lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender Web community. The robustness of the RDS method is tested by violating, one by one, the conditions under which the method provides unbiased estimates. Simulations indicate that the bias is large if networks are directed or respondents choose to invite people on the basis of characteristics that are correlated with the study outcomes. The bias and variance increase if participants invite close as opposed to more distant friends whereas sampling in denser networks sharply reduces variance. However, the RDS method shows strong resistance to sampling without replacement, low response rates and certain errors in the participants reporting of their network sizes, as well as the selection criteria of seeds. The effects of network structure and the number of seeds and coupons are also discussed.
WOS:000299154500009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="87">
<title>It Takes Two: The Interplay of Individual and Group Theology on Social Embeddedness</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-5906.2009.01427.x</url>
<snippet>Prior research argues that religious homophily in social networks is a product of overlapping interests and activities unintentionally leading to relationships or the intentional seeking of relationships with people of similar religious beliefs. This article advances research on religious homophily by including the role that exclusive theological beliefs play in explaining religious homophily among friends. We lay out three propositions for individual-, congregational-, and cross-level effects on the relationship between exclusive theology and embeddedness within one's congregation. Using multilevel models and data from the U.S. Congregational Life Survey (USCLS), we find support for our three propositions. We discuss our findings in terms of how exclusive theologies may contribute to bonding forms of social capital, but limit exposure to diverse social perspectives and bridging forms of social capital.
WOS:000263854100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="88">
<title>Top management team social capital, digital technology and enterprise innovation performance</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09537325.2023.2282067</url>
<snippet>Top management team (TMT) social capital plays an important role in obtaining innovation resources and improving enterprise innovation performance (EIP). However, there are few literatures on the impact of different dimensions of TMT social capital on EIP, especially in the digital era. Taking the listed companies disclosed by Shanghai Stock Exchange in 2008-2019 as samples, based on resource-based view and social network theory, a moderated mediation model is constructed. This paper examines the mechanism of TMT social capital affecting EIP, the mediating role of digital technology and the moderating role of network position. The results show that, TMT overseas capital and academic capital have significant positive effects on EIP; digital technology mediates the relationship between overseas capital, academic capital and EIP; network position moderates the relationship between academic capital and digital technology. Furthermore, the mediating role of digital technology in the relationship between academic capital and EIP is moderated by network position. The research conclusion enriches the research on TMT social capital, digital technology and EIP, and provides helpful guidance for enterprises to make full use of TMT social capital to manage digital technology and improve EIP.
WOS:001100491600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="89">
<title>Taking Communities into the Groan Zone: Subjective Wellbeing in the Face of Demographic Change, Racial Diversity, and Political Difference&lt;SUP&gt;&lt;/SUP&gt;</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ruso.12472</url>
<snippet>This paper draws from a dataset focusing on two rural communities in Colorado (USA). Data collection occurred over two periods: late-2019 and again during COVID-19 lockdowns in mid-2020. The communities differed demographically: one had a growing minoritized population, especially among its youth; the other was overwhelmingly white. The paper troubles the concept of subjective wellbeing (SWB) as it asks about the productive potentials of discomfort, with assistance from such concepts as colorblind ideology, motivated reasoning, and network homophily. While important to think about so-called positive emotional states in the context of community development, we must also ask questions like, "SWB for who and at whose expense?" How respondents thought about individual- and community-level SWB had much to do with the social networks they were in. I also explore why the community that fared pandemic-related disruptions, from a SWB standpoint, better than the other performed worse during this same period from an economic (material) standpoint. Sociological factors explain these dynamics, which are leveraged to enhance our understanding of how to conceptualize community development in productive ways. In sum, I argue that certain expressions of discomfort have value and are therefore necessary for creating resilient, flourishing, and, ultimately, just communities.
WOS:000883348900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="90">
<title>An Economic Model of Friendship: Homophily, Minorities, and Segregation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3982/ECTA7528</url>
<snippet>We develop a model of friendship formation that sheds light on segregation patterns observed in social and economic networks. Individuals have types and see type-dependent benefits from friendships. We examine the properties of a steady-state equilibrium of a matching process of friendship formation. We use the model to understand three empirical patterns of friendship formation: (i) larger groups tend to form more same-type ties and fewer other-type ties than small groups, (ii) larger groups form more ties per capita, and (iii) all groups are biased towards same-type relative to demographics, with the most extreme bias coming from middle-sized groups. We show how these empirical observations can be generated by biases in preferences and biases in meetings. We also illustrate some welfare implications of the model.
WOS:000268218600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="91">
<title>Getting along to get ahead: The role of social context in tournament promotion and reward systems</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0257389</url>
<snippet>Tournament theory posits that some organizations are modeled after sports tournaments whereby individuals are incentivized to compete and win against other members of the organization. A persistent criticism of tournament theory is that rank-order success of employees is entirely dependent on non-interacting or at least non-cooperating entities. To address what part, if any, cooperation plays in competitive tournaments, this study examines the role of social networks in tournament-style promotion and reward systems. Specifically, we seek to identify the importance of social relationships, such as group dissimilarity, initial tie formation, and tie strength in predicting tournament success. Bringing two largely independent research streams together (one focused on cooperation and one framed around competition), we examine how individuals' performance interacts with their social relationships-their social networks-to influence their chances of winning a tournament. Using the Survivor television series, we analyze the behaviors of 535 interacting contestants across 30 tournaments. In general, the findings help to illustrate how performance and social networks predict tournament advancement. Interestingly, we find that group dissimilarity based on gender, race, and age, largely does not play a role in advancement in the tournaments. Further, the strength of ties fails to mediate between variables such as group dissimilarity and initial tie formation. We conclude by discussing future directions for theoretical and practical exploration of tournament-style promotion systems. Recommendations include continuing to explore and test the role of social dynamics in compensation and promotion systems.
WOS:000707078200031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="92">
<title>Cultural Resources and Mobilization of Social Capital: The Case of Finding a Job</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/soin.12500</url>
<snippet>By combining the latest knowledge from cultural sociology and social network theories, a hypothesis is posed regarding the association between cultural consumption and social capital mobilization. On the classic example of looking for work, an assumption was made that persons who prefer or engage in a larger number of cultural forms (the so-called omnivores) have greater chances to find work through social contacts than through any other methods or may count on social support when looking for job, and this relationship is stronger for non-family than for family ties. These arguments are tested with the use of survey data collected in Poland in 2017 on a locally representative sample of adult residents aged 18-75. The results support the hypotheses and additionally show that people with different cultural profiles differ in their capacity to access and mobilize social resources. While participation in both highbrow and popular culture is efficacious, not all forms of the popular one are positively related to social resources. The article is closed with some concluding remarks, limitations of the study, and guidelines for future research.
WOS:000819582200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="93">
<title>Topological measures for identifying and predicting the spread of complex contagions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-24704-6</url>
<snippet>The standard measure of distance in social networks - average shortest path length - assumes a model of "simple" contagion, in which people only need exposure to influence from one peer to adopt the contagion. However, many social phenomena are "complex" contagions, for which people need exposure to multiple peers before they adopt. Here, we show that the classical measure of path length fails to define network connectedness and node centrality for complex contagions. Centrality measures and seeding strategies based on the classical definition of path length frequently misidentify the network features that are most effective for spreading complex contagions. To address these issues, we derive measures of complex path length and complex centrality, which significantly improve the capacity to identify the network structures and central individuals best suited for spreading complex contagions. We validate our theory using empirical data on the spread of a microfinance program in 43 rural Indian villages. Understanding of complex contagions is crucial for explaining diffusion processes in networks. Guilbeault and Centola introduce topological mechanisms and measures to elucidate spreading dynamics and identify the most influential nodes in social, epidemic and economic networks.
WOS:000677642700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="94">
<title>Core-periphery or decentralized? Topological shifts of specialized information on Twitter</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2017.09.006</url>
<snippet>In this paper we investigate shifts in Twitter network topology resulting from the type of information being shared. We identified communities matching areas of agricultural expertise and measured the core-periphery centralization of network formations resulting from users sharing generic versus specialized information. We found that centralization increases when specialized information is shared and that the network adopts decentralized formations as conversations become more generic. The results are consistent with classical diffusion models positing that specialized information comes with greater centralization, but they also show that users favor decentralized formations, which can foster community cohesion, when spreading specialized information is secondary. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000416496300026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="95">
<title>Reciprocity, transitivity, and skew: Comparing local structure in 40 positive and negative social networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0267886</url>
<snippet>While most social network research focuses on positive relational ties, such as friendship and information exchange, scholars are beginning to examine the dark side of human interaction, where negative connections represent different forms of interpersonal conflict, intolerance, and abuse. Despite this recent work, the extent to which positive and negative social network structure differs remains unclear. The current project considers whether a network's small-scale, structural patterns of reciprocity, transitivity, and skew, or its "structural signature," can distinguish positive versus negative links. Using exponential random graph models (ERGMs), we examine these differences across a sample of twenty distinct, negative networks and generate comparisons with a related set of twenty positive graphs. Relational ties represent multiple types of interaction such as like versus dislike in groups of adults, friendship versus cyberaggression among adolescents, and agreements versus disputes in online interaction. We find that both positive and negative networks contain more reciprocated dyads than expected by random chance. At the same time, patterns of transitivity define positive but not negative graphs, and negative networks tend to exhibit heavily skewed degree distributions. Given the unique structural signatures of many negative graphs, our results highlight the need for further theoretical and empirical research on the patterns of harmful interaction.
WOS:001044846900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="96">
<title>Exposure to opposing views on social media can increase political polarization</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1804840115</url>
<snippet>There is mounting concern that social media sites contribute to political polarization by creating "echo chambers" that insulate people from opposing views about current events. We surveyed a large sample of Democrats and Republicans who visit Twitter at least three times each week about a range of social policy issues. One week later, we randomly assigned respondents to a treatment condition in which they were offered financial incentives to follow a Twitter bot for 1 month that exposed them to messages from those with opposing political ideologies (e.g., elected officials, opinion leaders, media organizations, and nonprofit groups). Respondents were resurveyed at the end of the month to measure the effect of this treatment, and at regular intervals throughout the study period to monitor treatment compliance. We find that Republicans who followed a liberal Twitter bot became substantially more conservative posttreatment. Democrats exhibited slight increases in liberal attitudes after following a conservative Twitter bot, although these effects are not statistically significant. Notwithstanding important limitations of our study, these findings have significant implications for the interdisciplinary literature on political polarization and the emerging field of computational social science.
WOS:000444257200059
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="97">
<title>Predicting Node Degree Centrality with the Node Prominence Profile</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep07236</url>
<snippet>Centrality of a node measures its relative importance within a network. There are a number of applications of centrality, including inferring the influence or success of an individual in a social network, and the resulting social network dynamics. While we can compute the centrality of any node in a given network snapshot, a number of applications are also interested in knowing the potential importance of an individual in the future. However, current centrality is not necessarily an effective predictor of future centrality. While there are different measures of centrality, we focus on degree centrality in this paper. We develop a method that reconciles preferential attachment and triadic closure to capture a node's prominence profile. We show that the proposed node prominence profile method is an effective predictor of degree centrality. Notably, our analysis reveals that individuals in the early stage of evolution display a distinctive and robust signature in degree centrality trend, adequately predicted by their prominence profile. We evaluate our work across four real-world social networks. Our findings have important implications for the applications that require prediction of a node's future degree centrality, as well as the study of social network dynamics.
WOS:000346254800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="98">
<title>Transition of social organisations driven by gift relationships</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/s41599-023-01688-w</url>
<snippet>Anthropologists have observed that gifts bring goods to the recipient and honour to the donor in many human societies. The totality of such social relationships constitutes a network. Social networks characterise different types of social organisations including bands of small kin groups, tribal unions of families, and hierarchically organised chiefdoms. However, the factors and mechanisms that cause the transition between these types have hardly been explained. Here, we focus on gifts as the driving force for such changes. We build the model by idealising gift interactions and simulating the consequent social changes due to long-term massive interactions. In the model, people give their wealth to each other, produce wealth, and reciprocate for the gift. Gifts and reciprocation strengthen relationships. Through simulation, we demonstrate that, as the frequency and scale of gifts increase, economic and social disparities successively arise. Simultaneously, network structures shift from bands to tribes and then, chiefdoms. Statistical analysis using the Standard Cross-Cultural Sample, a global ethnographic database, empirically verifies the theoretical results. The constructive simulation study, as presented here, explains how people's interactions shape various social structures in response to environmental conditions. It provides the basic mechanistic explanation for social evolution and integrates microscopic and macroscopic theories in social sciences.
WOS:000978608000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="99">
<title>Getting to Know You: Welfare Fraud Investigation and the Appropriation of Social Ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0003122418818198</url>
<snippet>State-level public assistance agencies completed nearly a million SNAP fraud investigations in fiscal year 2016. These investigations hinge on compiling incriminating information about clients. Drawing on interviews with welfare fraud workers in five U.S. states, this article shows how fraud investigators creatively exploit clients' social networks to extract such information, and thus use clients' social ties against them. Investigators gain some information through elective cooperation, when people voluntarily implicate others. Fraud workers say these denunciations typically arise from negative-valence ties (bad blood). Other times, investigators co-opt neutral or positive-valence ties (good will) for enforcement purposes. This co-optation includes eliciting information from unwitting acquaintances and exploiting clients' own online social networking activity. These findings demonstrate social ties' appropriability, through which they serve as resources for relational outsiders' interests. Repurposing welfare clients' social ties for fraud enforcement presents a two-fold threat to subsistence and social mobility prospects: it imposes punishments-including program disqualifications-while simultaneously damaging social support networks. These enforcement practices reveal appropriability as an unrecognized property of social ties, particularly for socioeconomically marginalized people, and constitute a noteworthy element of contemporary poverty governance.
WOS:000458872100007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="100">
<title>Using GPS Technology to Quantify Human Mobility, Dynamic Contacts and Infectious Disease Dynamics in a Resource-Poor Urban Environment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0058802</url>
<snippet>Empiric quantification of human mobility patterns is paramount for better urban planning, understanding social network structure and responding to infectious disease threats, especially in light of rapid growth in urbanization and globalization. This need is of particular relevance for developing countries, since they host the majority of the global urban population and are disproportionally affected by the burden of disease. We used Global Positioning System (GPS) data-loggers to track the fine-scale (within city) mobility patterns of 582 residents from two neighborhoods from the city of Iquitos, Peru. We used similar to 2.3 million GPS data-points to quantify age-specific mobility parameters and dynamic co-location networks among all tracked individuals. Geographic space significantly affected human mobility, giving rise to highly local mobility kernels. Most (similar to 80&#37;) movements occurred within 1 km of an individual's home. Potential hourly contacts among individuals were highly irregular and temporally unstructured. Only up to 38&#37; of the tracked participants showed a regular and predictable mobility routine, a sharp contrast to the situation in the developed world. As a case study, we quantified the impact of spatially and temporally unstructured routines on the dynamics of transmission of an influenza-like pathogen within an Iquitos neighborhood. Temporally unstructured daily routines (e.g., not dominated by a single location, such as a workplace, where an individual repeatedly spent significant amount of time) increased an epidemic's final size and effective reproduction number by 20&#37; in comparison to scenarios modeling temporally structured contacts. Our findings provide a mechanistic description of the basic rules that shape human mobility within a resource-poor urban center, and contribute to the understanding of the role of fine-scale patterns of individual movement and co-location in infectious disease dynamics. More generally, this study emphasizes the need for careful consideration of human social interactions when designing infectious disease mitigation strategies, particularly within resource-poor urban environments.
WOS:000317898000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="101">
<title>Wild animals suppress the spread of socially transmitted misinformation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2215428120</url>
<snippet>Understanding the mechanisms by which information and misinformation spread through groups of individual actors is essential to the prediction of phenomena ranging from coordinated group behaviors to misinformation epidemics. Transmission of information through groups depends on the rules that individuals use to transform the perceived actions of others into their own behaviors. Because it is often not possible to directly infer decision-making strategies in situ, most studies of behavioral spread assume that individuals make decisions by pooling or averaging the actions or behavioral states of neighbors. However, whether individuals may instead adopt more sophisticated strategies that exploit socially transmitted information, while remaining robust to misinformation, is unknown. Here, we study the relationship between individual decision-making and misinformation spread in groups of wild coral reef fish, where misinformation occurs in the form of false alarms that can spread contagiously through groups. Using automated visual field reconstruction of wild animals, we infer the precise sequences of socially transmitted visual stimuli perceived by individuals during decision-making. Our analysis reveals a feature of decision-making essential for controlling misinformation spread: dynamic adjustments in sensitivity to socially transmitted cues. This form of dynamic gain control can be achieved by a simple and biologically widespread decision-making circuit, and it renders individual behavior robust to natural fluctuations in misinformation exposure.
WOS:001050365600004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="102">
<title>Using Ego Network Data to Inform Agent-based Models of Diffusion</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0049124118769100</url>
<snippet>Agent-based modeling holds great potential as an analytical tool. Agent-based models (ABMs) are, however, also vulnerable to critique, as they often employ stylized social worlds, with little connection to the actual environment in question. Given these concerns, there has been a recent call to more fully incorporate empirical data into ABMs. This article falls in this tradition, exploring the benefits of using sampled ego network data in ABMs of cultural diffusion. Thus, instead of relying on full network data, which can be difficult and costly to collect, or no empirical network data, which is convenient but not empirically grounded, we offer a middle-ground, one combining ABMs with recent work on network sampling. The main question is whether this approach is effective. We provide a test of the approach using six complete networks; the test also includes a range of diffusion models (where actors follow different rules of adoption). For each network, we take a random ego network sample and use that sample to infer the full network structure. We then run a diffusion model through the known, complete networks, as well as the inferred networks, and compare the results. The results, on the whole, are quite strong: Across all analyses, the diffusion curves based on the sampled data are very similar to the curves based on the true, complete network. This suggests that ego network sampling can, in fact, offer a practical means of incorporating empirical data into an agent-based model.
WOS:000591203300006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="103">
<title>Testing the validity of social capital measures in the study of information and communication technologies</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2014.884612</url>
<snippet>Social capital has been considered a cause and consequence of various uses of new information and communication technologies (ICTs). However, there is a growing divergence between how social capital is commonly measured in the study of ICTs and how it is measured in other fields. This departure raises questions about the validity of some of the most widely cited studies of social capital and ICTs. We compare the Internet Social Capital Scales (ISCS) developed by Williams [2006. On and off the 'net: scales for social capital in an online era. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 11(2), 593-628. doi: 10.1111/j.1083-6101.2006.00029.x] - a series of psychometric scales commonly used to measure 'social capital' - to established, structural measures of social capital: name, position, and resource generators. Based on a survey of 880 undergraduate students (the population to which the ISCS has been most frequently administered), we find that, unlike structural measures, the ISCS does not distinguish between the distinct constructs of bonding and bridging social capital. The ISCS does not have convergent validity with structural measures of bonding or bridging social capital; it does not measure the same concept as structural measures. The ISCS conflates social capital with the related constructs of social support and attachment. The ISCS does not measure perceived or actual social capital. These findings raise concerns about the interpretations of existing studies of 'social capital' and ICTs that are based on the ISCS. Given the absence of measurement validity, we urge those studying social capital to abandon the ISCS in favor of alternative approaches.
WOS:000333870700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="104">
<title>Netville online and offline - Observing and surveying a wired suburb</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/00027649921955290</url>
<snippet>Since the mid-1850s, scholars have debated how technological innovation would affect community. The debate continues as the Internet makes it increasingly possible for people to socialize, shop, work, learn, and participate in leisure activities all from within their home. Will the movement of these previously public activities into the private realm lead to reduced participation in public activities? What will be the fate of community and social relations as a result of the growth of computer-mediated communication? Netville is a suburban Toronto development equipped with a high-speed network as part of its design. The clustering of homes within this area allowed us to study the social networks, civic involvement, Internet use, and attitudes of residents. This article explores the research approach of the Netville project and describes its main sources of data collection: surveys collected using computer assisted interviewing and ethnographic fieldwork.
WOS:000082975900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="105">
<title>The antecedents of a 'chilly climate' for women faculty in higher education</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0018726710377932</url>
<snippet>The literature on women's under-representation in academia asserts that faculty women face a 'chilly climate', but there are few theoretically based studies examining this proposition. Relational demography, organizational justice, and social network theories all identify possible antecedents of 'chilly climate'. Using survey data of faculty at a private Midwestern US university, we test whether the perception of exclusion ( chilly climate) is influenced by demographic dissimilarity, and perceptions of fairness and gender equity. We find that faculty women perceive more exclusion from academic departments with a low representation of women, consistent with relational demography. Perceptions of procedural fairness and gender equity are powerful factors that foster inclusion and warm the climate for both men and women. The 'chilly climate' for women faculty is a complex phenomenon with multiple causes. Policies that fail to address these multiple causes are unlikely to be effective.
WOS:000287803200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="106">
<title>Some days are better than others: Examining time-specific variation in the structuring of interorganizational relations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2018.10.001</url>
<snippet>The generative mechanisms controlling change in interorganizational relations are typically assumed to be time- independent, i.e., operate homogeneously and synchronously over time. In this paper we consider some of the implications of violating this assumption. We adopt and extend statistical models for relational events to reveal time-specific variations in mechanisms underlying interorganizational relations observed within a small community of health care organizations. We find that aggregate estimates of parameters associated with mechanisms of theoretical interest mask fine-grained temporal variation in relational events sequences. We discuss the implications of this result for studies of interorganizational relations - and social networks snore generally.
WOS:000458224300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="107">
<title>When Do Haters Act? Peer Evaluation, Negative Relationships, and Brokerage</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.15195/v11.a16</url>
<snippet>In many organizational settings, individuals make evaluations in the context of affect -based negative relationships, in which an evaluator personally dislikes the evaluated individual. However, these dislikes are often held in check by norms of professionalism that preclude the use of personal preferences in objective evaluations. In this article, we draw from social network theory to suggest that only individuals that are network brokers-those who have the cognitive freedom to flout organizational norms-act to down -evaluate the peers they dislike. We evaluate our theory using two complementary studies: one field site study and an experiment. Our results, consistent across two different methodologies, suggest that overlooking an evaluator's negative relationships as well as the network positions that constrain or enable an individual's actions may lead to distortions in ubiquitous organizational peer evaluations processes and outcomes.
WOS:001237029400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="108">
<title>OMGs! Offline-based movement organizations, online-based movement organizations and network mobilization: a case study of political bloggers in Singapore</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2013.808256</url>
<snippet>The proliferation of Internet technologies has paved the way for technology adoption among marginalized communities and individuals for advancing varied political and civic agendas. Social movement scholars advocate that technology is becoming an integral component of the social movement repertoire, and building on their work, Internet scholars have examined the evolving nature of movement organizations and formal networks. Adopting resource mobilization and social network theories as the conceptual framework, this study examines political bloggers' social networks. Through 41 in-depth interviews and 76 survey responses, we collected data on political bloggers' activism participation and their organizational affiliations. Social networking patterns are linked to different organizational affiliation types - membership with formal organizations rooted in the offline context; membership with issue-based online organizations which assume a temporal nature and non-membership. Focusing on the dialectics between offline and online, permanence and temporality, the study showed that activists who belonged to offline-based organizations experienced greater social influence and collectiveness with one another. However, activist bloggers who belonged to online-based groups shared strong ties and sustained communication even after a campaign ended. More significantly, the findings show that online movement groups, although temporal in nature, foster what Sunstein [(2009). Republic.com 2.0 (pp. 19-45). Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press] termed as 'enclave deliberation', attributed to the inclusive and open networks of online-based movement organizations.
WOS:000333873900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="109">
<title>Based on Agent Model and &lt;i&gt;K&lt;/i&gt;-Core Decomposition to Analyze the Diffusion of Mass Incident in Microblog</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2017/6416795</url>
<snippet>Mass incidents, which may influence the stability and security of the society in China, are getting more and more attentions not only from policy makers but also from Chinese social researchers. Catching the diffusion mechanism is believed to be critical to understand essential of these mass incidents since message dissemination plays important roles in every stage of mass incident. Recently, online social networks including Weibo (Chinese Twitter) become more and more popular in China. There are reports showing that Weibo discussion has accompanied the processes of most mass incidents happening in China in these few years. So, in this paper, we aim at introducing. K-Core decomposition method from complex network to the analysis on how to manage the diffusion of mass incident in Weibo based on agent based model which can simulate Weibo user's actions when mass incident happens. This work can help people understand how mass incident messages spread across the network. And then, people may have better strategy to manage the diffusion of mass incidents.
WOS:000418813200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="110">
<title>DIFFERENTIAL PARTICIPATION IN PROFESSIONAL ACTIVISM: THE CASE OF THE GUANTANAMO HABEAS LAWYERS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Scholars of social movements tend to regard professionals as a homogeneous group whose activism plays a secondary role in mobilization processes. In this article, I focus on activism driven by professionals themselves and therein examine how heterogeneous professionals participate in their activism. Drawing on the case of the Guantanamo habeas lawyers, I utilize a two-step methodology to investigate the factors that contribute to the differential participation of legal professionals. The first stage of analysis shows that while lawyers with higher status played a critical role in initiating professional activism under a hostile environment, the Rasul v. Bush ruling opened up a legal opportunity for lawyers with lower status to participate in activism. In the second stage, social network analyses of the lawyers' collaborative structure reveal that movement-affiliated lawyers played a bridging role that coordinated initiators and latecomers. The results have important implications for understanding professionals' participation in contentious politics.
WOS:000346037700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="111">
<title>Modeling and Analysis of Dynamic Social Ties in D2D Collaborative Video Transmission</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2020/1915840</url>
<snippet>Social networks are one of the main carriers of information diffusion. Changes in social ties will affect the quality of Device-to-Device (D2D) communications especially the video transmission. For further improving the communication utility of users, it is of great significance to effectively integrate D2D communications and social networks. To this end, this paper utilizes a stochastic approach to modeling and analysis of dynamic social ties in D2D collaborative video transmission. Specifically, a stochastic mathematical model is established and analyzed, in which the combined effect of many factors such as interest, geographical position, career, social class, value system, and interaction is considered. Based on the Brownian motion theory, the strength of social ties among social individuals with time is studied. Next, the reliability function and adaptive parameter estimation are performed. Finally, some examples are conducted to illustrate the main results of this paper, from which one can see that the proposed model has a good predictive ability of the changing trend of social ties.
WOS:000549124200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="112">
<title>What are friends for? Elective communities of single people</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2008.07.001</url>
<snippet>The paper presents the results of a qualitative research on friendship networks of single people. The research has been undertaken using social network analysis tools (egonetworks) and qualitative interviews, on a non-representative sample of 23 heterosexual singles of Milan, aged between 25 and 35 years, 12 male and 11 female. Framed within the theory of community, we formulated some questions that are addressed through the analysis: the role of friendship in single people's everyday life, which in some cases substitutes the traditional family as a source of emotional, social, material and economical support; the possibility that friendship is not always intended as a source of support, and people can name friends even if they do not provide any kind of support; the effect of the network structure on the strength of dyads, that will easily disconnect if not embedded in a cohesive network. Four different kinds of friendship networks have been found: the small cliques, the company, the core/periphery structure, and the contextualised components. In the discussion section, empirical findings are analysed focusing on different strategies of friendship, and special attention is given to the gender issue. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000260367400005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="113">
<title>Who you know vs. what you know: The impact of social position and knowledge on team performance</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00222500500323101</url>
<snippet>Organizational behavior theories generally agree that human capital is critical to teams and organizations, but little guidance exists on the extent to which such theories accurately explain the relative contributions of individual actors to overall performance. Using newly created network measures and simulations based on data obtained from a software development firm, we investigate the relative effectiveness of social network theory and resource dependency theory as predictors of individuals' contributions to team performance. Our results indicate that individual impacts on team performance are more closely associated with knowledge and task dimensions than with social network structure. Furthermore, given that knowledge may be assessed a priori, these factors provide useful guidance for structuring teams and predicting team performance.
WOS:000233558600003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="114">
<title>Social network engineering and race in a police academy: A longitudinal analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2009.08.001</url>
<snippet>This research examined an attempt to facilitate racial integration by populating squads (i.e., workgroups) in a police academy with mixes of recruits that reflected the racial demographics of the larger cohort. This was part of the social infrastructure of the academy. Additionally, a fixed seating arrangement was considered as a second element of academy infrastructure capable of impacting racial integration. We examined the consequences of these academy components over time with regard to race by combining ethnographic accounts With social network data collected throughout the academy and using a variety of network analytic tools. These consequences with regard to race were examined as a part of social network evolution. The academy's social arrangements did accelerate the creation of social knowledge of recruits about each other and the formation of friendship ties both within and between races. However. our results point to cleat limitations to such infrastructural engineering and have implications for both recruitment to police academies and dealing with race. They shed light also oil processes of homophily and group composition over time and have implications for Studying social networks. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000274948700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="115">
<title>Neighborhood conditions and social network turnover among older adults</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2023.01.003</url>
<snippet>Increasing research highlights heterogeneity in patterns of social network change, with growing evidence that these patterns are shaped in part by social structure. The role of social and structural neighborhood conditions in the addition and loss of kin and non-kin network members, however, has not been fully considered. In this paper, we argue that the residential neighborhood context can either facilitate or prevent the turnover of core network relationships in later life - a period of the life course characterized by heightened reliance on network ties and vulnerability to neighborhood conditions. Using longitudinal data from the National Social Life, Health, and Aging Project linked with data from the American Community Survey, we find that higher levels of neighborhood concentrated disadvantage are associated with the loss of older adults' kin and non-kin network members over time. Higher levels of perceived neighborhood social interaction, however, are associated with higher rates of adding non-kin network members and lower rates of adding kin network members over time. We suggest that neighborhood conditions, including older adults' perceptions of neighborhood social life, represent an underexplored influence on kin and non-kin social network dynamics, which could have implications for access to social resources later in the life course.
WOS:000931603800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="116">
<title>Social Media and Protest Participation: Evidence From Russia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3982/ECTA14281</url>
<snippet>Do new communication technologies, such as social media, alleviate the collective action problem? This paper provides evidence that penetration of VK, the dominant Russian online social network, led to more protest activity during a wave of protests in Russia in 2011. As a source of exogenous variation in network penetration, we use the information on the city of origin of the students who studied with the founder of VK, controlling for the city of origin of the students who studied at the same university several years earlier or later. We find that a 10&#37; increase in VK penetration increased the probability of a protest by 4.6&#37; and the number of protesters by 19&#37;. Additional results suggest that social media induced protest activity by reducing the costs of coordination rather than by spreading information critical of the government. We observe that VK penetration increased pro-governmental support, with no evidence of increased polarization. We also find that cities with higher fractionalization of network users between VK and Facebook experienced fewer protests, and the effect of VK on protests exhibits threshold behavior.
WOS:000551174500009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="117">
<title>Link prediction on Twitter</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0181079</url>
<snippet>With over 300 million active users, Twitter is among the largest online news and social networking services in existence today. Open access to information on Twitter makes it a valuable source of data for research on social interactions, sentiment analysis, content diffusion, link prediction, and the dynamics behind human collective behaviour in general. Here we use Twitter data to construct co-occurrence language networks based on hashtags and based on all the words in tweets, and we use these networks to study link prediction by means of different methods and evaluation metrics. In addition to using five known methods, we propose two effective weighted similarity measures, and we compare the obtained outcomes in dependence on the selected semantic context of topics on Twitter. We find that hashtag networks yield to a large degree equal results as all-word networks, thus supporting the claim that hashtags alone robustly capture the semantic context of tweets, and as such are useful and suitable for studying the content and categorization. We also introduce ranking diagrams as an efficient tool for the comparison of the performance of different link prediction algorithms across multiple datasets. Our research indicates that successful link prediction algorithms work well in correctly foretelling highly probable links even if the information about a network structure is incomplete, and they do so even if the semantic context is rationalized to hashtags.
WOS:000406061400031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="118">
<title>Sustainability of Stack Exchange Q&amp;A communities: the role of trust</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjds/s13688-023-00381-x</url>
<snippet>Knowledge-sharing communities are fundamental elements of a knowledge-based society. Understanding how different factors influence their sustainability is of crucial importance. We explore the role of the social network structure and social trust in their sustainability. We analyze the early evolution of social networks in four pairs of active and closed Stack Exchange communities on topics of physics, astronomy, economics, and literature and use a dynamical reputation model to quantify the evolution of social trust in them. In addition, we study the evolution of two active communities on mathematics topics and two closed communities about startups and compare them with our main results. Active communities have higher local cohesiveness and develop stable, better-connected, trustworthy cores. The early emergence of a stable and trustworthy core may be crucial for sustainable knowledge-sharing communities.
WOS:000939362400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="119">
<title>Modelling Multilevel Interdependencies for Resilience in Complex Organisation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2019/3946356</url>
<snippet>This paper aims to model multilevel interdependencies in complex organisational systems and proposes application for resilience analysis. Most of the existing research studied interdependencies only at the single-level and overlooked their multilevel character. In response to this gap, we propose a multilevel approach to better comprehend the complexity of interdependencies in organisational systems. More specifically, the study focuses on how interdependencies are shaped across multiple organisational levels. To understand the research problem, we use multilevel and social network theories to elaborate the concept at five organisational levels, namely, individual, intraunit, interunit, intraorganisational, and interorganisational. Further, we show the application of multilevel interdependencies into analysis of organisational resilience. To this end, we construct a multiplex model of a real world organisational system that comprises formal and informal relations of different social exchange strength. Using the agent-based simulations of the organisational system, we investigate the relations between organisational interdependencies and organisational performance in normal and disrupted conditions. With the results, we argue that managing multilevel interdependencies is crucial to reduce vulnerability of organisational systems. By introducing the multilevel conceptualisation of interdependencies and presenting their influence on organisational resilience, we hope to pave a path to managing the complexity of interdependencies and strategic resilience enhancement in organisational systems.
WOS:000459668500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="120">
<title>Dynamics of Dyads in Social Networks: Assortative, Relational, and Proximity Mechanisms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1146/annurev.soc.34.040507.134743</url>
<snippet>Embeddedness in social networks is increasingly seen as a root cause of human achievement, social stratification, and actor behavior. In this article, we review sociological research that examines the processes through which dyadic ties form, persist, and dissolve. Three sociological mechanisms are overviewed: assortative mechanisms that draw attention to the role of actors' attributes, relational mechanisms that emphasize the influence of existing relationships and network positions, and proximity mechanisms that focus on the social organization of interaction.
WOS:000281254500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="121">
<title>DR-SCIR Public Opinion Propagation Model with Direct Immunity and Social Reinforcement Effect</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/sym12040584</url>
<snippet>The DR-SCIR network public opinion propagation model was employed to study the characters of S-state users stopping transmitting information for the first time and secondary transmission of immune users. The model takes into account symmetry and complexity such as direct immunization and social reinforcement effect, proposes the probability of direct immunity Psr and the probability of transform from the immune state to the hesitant state Prc, and divides public opinion information into positive public opinion and negative public opinion based on whether the public opinion information is confirmed. Simulation results show that, when direct immunity Psr = 0.5, the density of I-state nodes in the model decreased by 54.12&#37; at the peak index; when the positive social reinforcement effect factor b = 10, the density of I-state nodes in the model increased by 16.67&#37; at the peak index; and when the negative social reinforcement effect factor b = -10, the density of I-state nodes in the model decreased by 55.36&#37; at the peak index. It shows that increasing the positive social reinforcement effect factor b can promote the spread of positive public opinion, reducing the negative social reinforcement effect factor b can control the spread of negative public opinion, and direct immunization can effectively suppress the spread of public opinion. This model can help us better analyze the rules of public opinion on social networks, so as to maintain a healthy and harmonious network and social environment.
WOS:000540222200095
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="122">
<title>Network Diversity and Economic Development</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1186605</url>
<snippet>Social networks form the backbone of social and economic life. Until recently, however, data have not been available to study the social impact of a national network structure. To that end, we combined the most complete record of a national communication network with national census data on the socioeconomic well-being of communities. These data make possible a population-level investigation of the relation between the structure of social networks and access to socioeconomic opportunity. We find that the diversity of individuals' relationships is strongly correlated with the economic development of communities.
WOS:000277877100041
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="123">
<title>The web mirrors value in the real world: comparing a firm's valuation with its web network position</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10588-015-9189-6</url>
<snippet>This paper compares a firm's innovation and performance with its online Web presence measured through the Web network structure. 489 firms in five different industries listed on the United States and Chinese stock markets are investigated. Using Web link data collected from Bing, blogs, Twitter and Wikipedia, we find positive correlation between betweenness centrality of a firm in the Web network and its innovation capability; and between betweenness centrality and financial performance. In order to get more accurate forecasting results, regression analysis is done for each industry and the combined industries in the United States and China. We also find that Twitter and Wikipedia only predict a firm's performance in the United States, which is not surprising as they are officially blocked in China. Blogs predict better in China than they do in the United States, as it might still be a major social media tool for Chinese firms; while for the US firms, blogs have been supplemented by Twitter and Wikipedia.
WOS:000363967000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="124">
<title>An option-theoretic model of a reputation network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/0022250X.2018.1545769</url>
<snippet>This paper constructs a new theory of social networks based on reputation. The model assumes that reputation is an asset and that individuals connect by buying options on the reputation of others. In networking, individuals construct portfolios of call options to leverage the reputations of others and put options to hedge the connections with others. A network then consists of portfolios of reputation options. The option model confers advantages not present in existing models. First, the payoff to connecting is the payoff on a portfolio of reputation options. Second, the network forms as individuals take option positions; the network evolves as individuals adjust those positions. Third, networking strategies become option strategies. The model allows for insights into network structure, the price of connecting and the value of connecting.
WOS:000469134800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="125">
<title>Emergence of social support networks among breast cancer survivors through a community-based physical activity program in Colombia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2022.12.007</url>
<snippet>Physical activity (PA), social networks, and social support have been associated with decreased mortality and improved quality of life among breast cancer survivors (BCS). This study used social network analysis to un-derstand the social co-benefits of a community-based PA program for BCS in Colombia. Two types of social support networks emerged from the program: friendship (the number of edges increased by 90 &#37;) and PA support (35 &#37; of participants practiced PA together after the program). Using egocentric and socio-centric analysis we show the presence of homophily for friendship and PA support relations and the BCS's roles in their networks.
WOS:000918760600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="126">
<title>Coupling human mobility and social ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2014.1128</url>
<snippet>Studies using massive, passively collected data from communication technologies have revealed many ubiquitous aspects of social networks, helping us understand and model social media, information diffusion and organizational dynamics. More recently, these data have come tagged with geographical information, enabling studies of human mobility patterns and the science of cities. We combine these two pursuits and uncover reproducible mobility patterns among social contacts. First, we introduce measures of mobility similarity and predictability and measure them for populations of users in three large urban areas. We find individuals' visitations patterns are far more similar to and predictable by social contacts than strangers and that these measures are positively correlated with tie strength. Unsupervised clustering of hourly variations in mobility similarity identifies three categories of social ties and suggests geography is an important feature to contextualize social relationships. We find that the composition of a user's ego network in terms of the type of contacts they keep is correlated with mobility behaviour. Finally, we extend a popular mobility model to include movement choices based on social contacts and compare its ability to reproduce empirical measurements with two additional models of mobility.
WOS:000351230700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="127">
<title>WHEN EXPERIENCE COUNTS - THE EFFECTS OF EXPERIENTIAL AND STRUCTURAL SIMILARITY ON PATTERNS OF SUPPORT AND INTERPERSONAL STRESS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/2580459</url>
<snippet>Previous research has suggested that individuals benefit from having associates who are similar to themselves on a variety of dimensions. This article develops a theoretical basis for predicting which types of similarity are most important in determining whether associates will be sources of social support or interpersonal stress. Drawing upon theories of homophily and reference groups, we suggest that experiential similarity (e.g., having experienced a similar status transition) is more important than structural similarity (e.g., similarity of age, gender, marital status) in determining sources of emotional support and stress following life events. The theoretical arguments are supported by data from two separate longitudinal studies of social networks following status transitions; specifically, returning to school and becoming the primary caregiver to an elderly parent.
WOS:A1995RJ51200019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="128">
<title>Institutional Investor Information Sharing, Stock Market Extreme Risk, and Financial Systemic Risk</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2020/5745916</url>
<snippet>To analyze whether information sharing in the institutional investors plays the role of a market stabilizer or risk booster, this paper constructs the institutional investor information network employing the common holding stocks of the mutual funds as links. The information linkages between two funds with large positions in the same stock are hypothesized to be connected to each other. Then, we use the information sharing efficiency in the fund networks to study the effects of information transmission on stock market extreme risk and financial systemic risk. Especially, the speed of information diffusion in the network is characterized by the topology structures based on social network theory. Empirical research studies find that the Chinese fund information network exhibits small-world characteristics, which reflects rapid speed of information diffusion. Seen from the idiosyncratic risk of volatility, information sharing of institutional investors can improve the behavior consistency of fund managers, thus increasing the stock volatility via herd effects. Besides, it can be concluded that institutional investor information sharing can reduce the extreme risk by promoting the comprehensiveness of information flow and the market pricing efficiency of stocks, thereby reducing the degree of financial systemic risk. The obtained conclusions provide suggestions for decision-making of institutional investors. It can help the regulators to pay attention to the herd effects so as to control systemic risk.
WOS:000530247700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="129">
<title>Emergent social cohesion for coping with community disruptions in disasters</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2019.0778</url>
<snippet>Social cohesion is an important determinant of community well-being, especially in times of distress such as disasters. This study investigates the phenomena of emergent social cohesion, which is characterized by abrupt, temporary and extensive social ties with the goal of sharing and receiving information regarding a particular event influencing a community. In the context of disasters, emergent social cohesion, enabled by social media usage, could play a significant role in improving the ability of communities to cope with disruptions in recent disasters. In this study, we employed a network reticulation framework to examine the underlying mechanisms influencing emergent social cohesion on social media while communities cope with disaster-induced disruptions. We analysed neighbourhood-tagged social media data (social media data whose users are tagged by neighbourhoods) in Houston, TX, USA, during Hurricane Harvey to characterize four modalities of network reticulation (i.e. enactment, activation, reticulation and performance) giving rise to emergent social cohesion. Our results show that, unlike regular social cohesion, communication history and physical proximity do not significantly affect emergent social cohesion. The results also indicate that weak social ties play an important role in bridging different social network communities, and hence reinforce emergent social cohesion. The findings can inform public officials, emergency managers and decision-makers regarding the important role of neighbourhood-tagged social media, as a new form of community infrastructure, for improving the ability of communities to cope with disaster disruptions through enhanced emergent social cohesion.
WOS:000519223100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="130">
<title>Cumulative Dynamics of Independent Information Spreading Behaviour: A Physical Perspective</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-05899-5</url>
<snippet>The popularization of information spreading in online social networks facilitates daily communication among people. Although much work has been done to study the effect of interactions among people on spreading, there is less work that considers the pattern of spreading behaviour when people independently make their decisions. By comparing microblogging, an important medium for information spreading, with the disordered spin glass system, we find that there exist interesting corresponding relationships between them. And the effect of aging can be observed in both systems. Based on the analogy with the Trap Model of spin glasses, we derive a model with a unified powerfunction form for the growth of independent spreading activities. Our model takes several key factors into consideration, including memory effect, the dynamics of human interest, and the fact that older messages are more difficult to discover. We validate our model by a real-world microblogging data set. Our work indicates that, other than various features, some invariable rules should be considered during spreading prediction. This work also contributes a useful methodology for studying human dynamics.
WOS:000405675400010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="131">
<title>Network structure and team performance: The case of English Premier League soccer teams</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2012.08.004</url>
<snippet>A defining feature of a work group is how its individual members interact. Building on a dataset of 283,259 passes between professional soccer players, this study applies mixed-effects modeling to 76 repeated observations of the interaction networks and performance of 23 soccer teams. Controlling for unobserved characteristics, such as the quality of the teams, the study confirms previous findings with panel data: networks characterized by high intensity (controlling for interaction opportunities) and low centralization are indeed associated with better team performance. 
WOS:000313304100030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="132">
<title>The Mechanism Explaining the Effect of HEXACO Traits on Vietnamese University Graduates' Networking Behavior for Finding Employment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/21582440231178260</url>
<snippet>This study examines the relationships between university graduates' HEXACO traits and networking behavior for finding a job through job search network size. We integrate individual difference theory and social network theory to explain these links in two manners. We use individual difference theory to demonstrate that graduates with HEXACO personality traits have different job search network sizes, and we apply social network theory to test whether job search network size affect the networking intensity of graduates. The sample of 773 graduates was collected at two points with a 3 months-lagged time. Our results suggest that three HEXACO traits had an effect on job search network size. At the same time, job search network size play role in increasing networking behavior. Specifically, job search network size served as partial mediator in the relationships between HEXACO traits and networking behavior. The findings, theoretical, practical implications, and future research are discussed further.
WOS:001000929300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="133">
<title>The Recruitment Paradox: Network Recruitment, Structural Position, and East German Market Transition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/sf/sou100</url>
<snippet>Economic institutions structure links between labor-market informality and social stratification. The present study explores how periods of institutional change and post-socialist market transition alter network-based job finding, in particular informal recruitment. We highlight how market transitions affect both the prevalence and distribution of network-based recruitment channels: open-market environments reduce informal recruitment's prevalence but increase its association with high wages. We test these propositions using the case of the former East Germany's market transition and a comparison with West Germany's more stable institutional environment. Following transition, workers in lower tiers increasingly turned toward formal intermediaries, active employee search, and socially "disembedded" matches. Meanwhile, employers actively recruited workers into higher-wage positions. Implications for market transition theory and post-socialist stratification are discussed.
WOS:000351528800033
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="134">
<title>The influence of network structure and prosocial cultural norms on charitable giving: A multilevel analysis of Movember's fundraising campaigns in 24 countries</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2019.04.001</url>
<snippet>This study examines how the interplay between an online campaign's network structure and prosocial cultural norms in a country affect charitable giving. We conducted a multilevel analysis that includes Twitter network and aggregated donation data from the 2013 Movember fundraising campaigns in 24 countries during 62 campaign days. Prosocial cultural norms did not affect the relationship between network size and average donations raised, nor did they affect the relationship between network centralization and average donation amount. Prosocial cultural norms did affect the relationship between network density and average donations raised. However, this effect was negative and contrary to our expectation.
WOS:000472813200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="135">
<title>Social influence or selection? Peer effects on the development of adolescents' educational expectations in Germany</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01425692.2020.1763163</url>
<snippet>Educational expectations are a key predictor of educational attainment. Throughout adolescence, friends increasingly function as 'significant others' and, thus, can affect the development of these expectations. Although scholars often interpret the clustering of students with similar expectations within friendship networks as the outcome of peer influence, a similarity of friends can also be a result of friendship selection processes and preselection due to ability tracking. We apply multilevel social network models to panel data of adolescents from Germany (1,992 ninth-grade students in 91 classes) to disentangle these mechanisms. Beyond selecting similar friends (homophily), we find that adolescents adapt their expectations towards the average expectations of their friends (social influence) but only in secondary-school tracks that support diverse educational paths. We conclude that peer socialization is important for the development of students' educational expectations in contexts that are sufficiently heterogeneous to allow for the emergence of distinct peer milieus.
WOS:000545118000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="136">
<title>The origins of status hierarchies: A formal theory and empirical test</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/341744</url>
<snippet>This article offers a formal theoretical model of the emergence of hierarchy that bridges the division between individualistic and structuralist accounts of inequality. In the model, actors reproduce status hierarchies by adjusting their own status- conferring gestures according to collective attributions. These collective attributions are just the aggregate of individual gestures, leading to a self-reinforcing status ranking. Winner-take- all hierarchies are discouraged, however, when people prefer reciprocation of their status-conferring actions. The model therefore depicts a status ranking as an equilibrium resulting from individual responses to the trade- off between social influence and the distaste for making unreciprocated gestures. Analysis of the model generates several precise predictions about the patterns that social networks should exhibit at equilibrium. Data on interaction in task groups, friendship ratings in a fraternity, and play in a set of infant quintuplets is used to show that the formal theory makes unusually accurate predictions about network structure.
WOS:000177489800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="137">
<title>Intervention Strategies and the Diffusion of Collective Behavior</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.18564/jasss.2872</url>
<snippet>This paper examines the intervention strategies for the diffusion of collective behavior, such as promoting innovation adoption and repressing a strike. An intervention strategy refers to controlling the behaviors of a small number of individuals in terms of their social or personal attributes, including connectivity (i.e., the number of social ties one holds), motivation (i.e., an individual's intrinsic cost-benefit judgment on behavior change), and sensitivity (i.e., the degree to which one follows others). Extensive agent-based simulations demonstrate that the optimal strategy fundamentally depends on the goal and time of intervention. Moreover, the nature of the social network (determined by homophily type and level) moderates the effectiveness of a strategy. These results have substantial implications for the design and evaluation of intervention programs.
WOS:000369643200016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="138">
<title>Fishing Nets between Two Seas: Guilds and Ship-Owner Associations in the Atlantic and Mediterranean Fishing Grounds of Andalusia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5477/cis/reis.155.113</url>
<snippet>This study examines the organizational network of the extractive sector in Andalusian fishing enclaves. For this, we have evaluated 6 types of informal and institutional relationships between a total of 30 guilds and ship-owner associations in 21 Andalusian fishing ports. The analyzed networks were found to have a core-periphery structure with the guilds playing a central role. The QAP procedure was used to identify two distinct contexts of relationship formation: informal meetings and the government fishing network (corresponding to formal meetings, such as fishing tables, port assemblies and fishing quota negotiations). We verified the existence of significant homophily dynamics based on both fishing ground and organization type.
WOS:000380370000007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="139">
<title>Resources and relationships: Social networks and mobility in the workplace</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/2657354</url>
<snippet>We examine how the structure and content of individuals' networks in the workplace affect intraorganizational mobility. Consistent with prior research, we find that an. individual's mobility is enhanced by having a large, sparse network of informal ties for acquiring information and resources. However in contrast to previous work, we emphasize the importance of consistent role expectations for performance and mobility. We find evidence that well-defined performance expectations are more likely to arise from a small, dense network of individuals. We develop a typology of network contents and document the interaction between network structure and content in analyses of mobility among employees of a high-technology firm. We also examine how the effects of tie duration on mobility vary by tie content. We discuss the implications of our results for theory and research on networks and organizational mobility.
WOS:A1997YE11200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="140">
<title>Kinship Shapes Affiliative Social Networks but Not Aggression in Ring-Tailed Coatis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0037301</url>
<snippet>Animal groups typically contain individuals with varying degrees of genetic relatedness, and this variation in kinship has a major influence on patterns of aggression and affiliative behaviors. This link between kinship and social behavior underlies socioecological models which have been developed to explain how and why different types of animal societies evolve. We tested if kinship and age-sex class homophily in two groups of ring-tailed coatis (Nasua nasua) predicted the network structure of three different social behaviors: 1) association, 2) grooming, and 3) aggression. Each group was studied during two consecutive years, resulting in four group-years available for analysis (total of 65 individuals). Association patterns were heavily influenced by agonistic interactions which typically occurred during feeding competition. Grooming networks were shaped by mother-offspring bonds, female-female social relationships, and a strong social attraction to adult males. Mother-offspring pairs were more likely to associate and groom each other, but relatedness had no effect on patterns of aggressive behavior. Additionally, kinship had little to no effect on coalitionary support during agonistic interactions. Adult females commonly came to the aid of juveniles during fights with other group members, but females often supported juveniles who were not their offspring (57&#37; of coalitionary interactions). These patterns did not conform to predictions from socioecological models.
WOS:000305343500093
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="141">
<title>Good health and the bridging of structural holes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2008.10.005</url>
<snippet>Bridges that span structural holes are often explained in terms of the entrepreneurial personalities or rational motivations of brokers, or structural processes that lead to the intersection of social foci. I argue that the existence and use of bridges in interpersonal networks also depends on individuals' health. Poor health may make it more difficult to withstand the pressures and to execute some of the common tasks associated with bridging(e.g., brokerage). I examine this possibility using egocentric network data on over 2500 older adults drawn from the recent National Social Life, Health, and Aging Project (NSHAP). Multivariate regression analyses show that both cognitive and functional health are significantly positively associated with bridging, net of sociodemographic and life-course controls. The relationship between functional (kinesthetic) health and bridging appears to be partially mediated by network composition, as older adults who have poorer functional health also tend to have networks that are richer in strong ties. Several potential mediation mechanisms are discussed. Cognitive function remains significantly associated with bridging net of network composition, Suggesting that the inherent challenges of maintaining bridging positions may be more difficult to cope with for those who have cognitive impairments than for those who have functional impairments such as limited mobility. An alternative explanation is that cognitively impaired individuals have more difficulty recognizing (and thus strategically using) bridges in their networks. Theoretical implications and possibilities for future research are discussed. 
WOS:000262547600010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="142">
<title>Obstacle avoidance in social groups: new insights from asynchronous models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2015.0178</url>
<snippet>For moving animals, the successful avoidance of hazardous obstacles is an important capability. Despite this, few models of collective motion have addressed the relationship between behavioural and social features and obstacle avoidance. We develop an asynchronous individual-based model for social movement which allows social structure within groups to be included. We assess thedynamics of groupnavigation and resulting collision risk in the context of information transfer through the system. In agreement with previous work, we find that group size has a nonlinear effect on collision risk. We implement examples of possible network structures to explore the impact social preferences have on collision risk. We show that any social heterogeneity induces greater obstacle avoidance with further improvements corresponding to groups containing fewer influential individuals. The model provides a platform for both further theoretical investigation and practical application. In particular, we argue that the role of social structures within bird flocks may have an important role to play in assessing the risk of collisions with wind turbines, but that new methods of data analysis are needed to identify these social structures.
WOS:000353359900037
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="143">
<title>Bridging Boundaries? The Effect of Genetic Ancestry Testing on Ties across Racial Groups</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/socpro/spab082</url>
<snippet>The phenomenon of widespread genetic ancestry testing has raised questions about its social impact, particularly on issues of race. Some accounts suggest testing can promote bridging social capital - connections between racial groups. In this multi-method paper, we ask whether (1) taking genetic ancestry tests (GATs) and (2) receiving results of African, Asian, or Native American ancestry increases network racial diversity for White Americans. We use a randomized controlled trial of 802 White, non-Hispanic Americans, half of whom received GATs. Unexpected findings show that test-takers' network racial diversity decreases after testing. Using 58 follow-up interviews, we develop and test a possible theory, finding initial evidence that test-takers' network racial diversity declines because they reconsider their racial appraisals of others in their networks.
WOS:001081224700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="144">
<title>Unveiling the dynamics of emotions in society through an analysis of online social network conversations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-41573-9</url>
<snippet>Social networks can provide insights into the emotions expressed by a society. However, the dynamic nature of emotions presents a significant challenge for policymakers, politicians, and communication professionals who seek to understand and respond to changes in emotions over time. To address this challenge, this paper investigates the frequency, duration, and transition of 24 distinct emotions over a 2-year period, analyzing more than 5 million tweets. The study shows that emotions with lower valence but higher dominance and/or arousal are more prevalent in online social networks. Emotions with higher valence and arousal tend to last longer, while dominant emotions tend to have shorter durations. Emotions occupying the conversations predominantly inhibit others with similar valence and dominance, and higher arousal. Over a month, emotions with similar valences tend to prevail in online social network conversations.
WOS:001123496500025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="145">
<title>A bibliometric and visualization analysis of Artisan entrepreneurship</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09537325.2023.2290152</url>
<snippet>Artisan entrepreneurship is an important way to develop economic prosperity in cultural industry, but there is a lack of systematic and quantitative review guidance. With 818 SSCI documents from the Web of Science database from 1992 to 2022, this paper uses bibliometric and visualization analysis methods to review and sort out the research in the field of artisan entrepreneurship, reveal the knowledge base and research hotspots, and put forward suggestions and outlook. The study finds that the knowledge bases of artisan entrepreneurship research include cultural entrepreneurship theory, resources-based theory, social network theory, family entrepreneurship theory and micro-theory of tourism industry development. The research hotspots focus on six themes: artisan entrepreneurs, entrepreneurial drivers, factors influencing the entrepreneurial process of artisans, economic value, cultural values, and social values. Finally, the existing theoretical framework of artisan entrepreneurship is integrated and future research directions and perspectives are proposed from six perspectives.
WOS:001124814400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="146">
<title>Community responses to national healthcare firms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Over the last 25 years, national Health Maintenance Organization (HMO) and hospital firms attempted to enter local markets, either by acquiring formerly independent, locally based HMOs and hospitals or by directly entering local markets. While national HMOs have been relatively successful, national hospital firms have had much less success. This paper explores the reasons for this difference. It reviews changes in presence of national HMO and hospital firms in markets, discusses common conceptual lenses through which national entry into local markets typically has been viewed, and shows how social network theory can be used to develop a better understanding of why the entry experience of national HMO and hospital firms varies across markets. The paper concludes with a research agenda that addresses issues raised by social network theory and its application to national firm entry into local markets.
WOS:000240599700009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="147">
<title>Hegemonic and Other Masculinities in Local Social Contexts</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1097184X06298776</url>
<snippet>This article is a theoretical examination of Connell's social theory of gender, discussing how hegemonic, complicit, subordinate, and marginalized masculinities interact and relate to one another in the men's everyday lives in particular social contexts. Connell's theory is articulated in global terms that need to be localized to examine the actual interactions of men with one another. The theory implies a multilevel framework that the authors develop more explicitly. They investigate two interrelated theoretical concerns: (a) inadequately detailed interdependencies between structural, individual, and cultural factors with respect to masculinities, and (b) the lack of contextualization of masculinities in specific relational settings. The authors suggest that theoretical insights gained from social network theory and analysis allow such issues to be addressed and assist in local-level accounts of gendered power relations. The authors conclude by specifying Connell's theory into particular, testable hypotheses for use with statistical models for social networks.
WOS:000266430300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="148">
<title>The "unfriending" problem: The consequences of homophily in friendship retention for causal estimates of social influence</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2011.05.003</url>
<snippet>An increasing number of scholars are using longitudinal social network data to try to obtain estimates of peer or social influence effects. These data may provide additional statistical leverage, but they can introduce new inferential problems. In particular, while the confounding effects of homophily in friendship formation are widely appreciated, homophily in friendship retention may also confound causal estimates of social influence in longitudinal network data. We provide evidence for this claim in a Monte Carlo analysis of the statistical model used by Christakis, Fowler. and their colleagues in numerous articles estimating "contagion" effects in social networks. Our results indicate that homophily in friendship retention induces significant upward bias and decreased coverage levels in the Christakis and Fowler model if there is non-negligible friendship attrition over time. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000294520200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="149">
<title>Network Sampling with Memory: A Proposal for More Efficient Sampling from Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0081175012461248</url>
<snippet>Techniques for sampling from networks have grown into an important area of research across several fields. For sociologists, the possibility of sampling from a network is appealing for two reasons: (1) A network sample can yield substantively interesting data about network structures and social interactions, and (2) it is useful in situations in which study populations are difficult or impossible to survey with traditional sampling approaches because of the lack of a sampling frame. Despite its appeal, methodological concerns about the precision and accuracy of network-based sampling methods remain. In particular, recent research has shown that sampling from a network using a random walk-based approach such as respondent-driven sampling (RDS) can result in a high design effect (DE): the ratio of the sampling variance to the sampling variance of simple random sampling (SRS). A high DE means that more cases must be collected to achieve the same level of precision as SRS. In this article, we propose an alternative strategy, network sampling with memory (NSM), which collects network data from respondents to reduce DEs and, correspondingly, the number of interviews needed to achieve a given level of statistical power. NSM combines a "list'' mode, in which all individuals on the revealed network list are sampled with the same cumulative probability, with a "search'' mode, which gives priority to bridge nodes connecting the current sample to unexplored parts of the network. We test the relative efficiency of NSM compared with RDS and SRS on 162 school and university networks from the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health and Facebook that range in size from 110 to 16,278 nodes. The results show that the average DE for NSM on these 162 networks is 1.16, which is very close to the efficiency of a simple random sample (DE = 1) and 98.5 percent lower than the average DE we observed for RDS.
WOS:000339965700014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="150">
<title>Measuring transnational social fields through binational link-tracing sampling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0253042</url>
<snippet>We advance bi-national link-tracing sampling design, an innovative data collection methodology for sampling from so-called "transnational social fields", i.e. transnational networks embedding migrants, returned migrants and non-migrants. This paper describes our contributions to this methodology and its empirical implementation, and evaluates the features of the resulting networks (sample), with the aim to guide future research. We performed 303 face-to-face structured interviews on sociodemographic variables, migration trajectories and personal networks of people living in a Romanian migration sending community (Dambovi?a) and in a migration receiving Spanish town (Castellon). Inter-connecting the personal networks, we built a multi-layered complex network structure embedding 4,855 nominated people, 5,477 directed ties (nominations) and 2,540 edges. Results indicate that the link-tracing nomination patterns are affected by sex and residence homophily. Our research contributes to the emerging efforts of applying social network analysis to the study of international migration.
WOS:000664643500022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="151">
<title>A natural experiment of social network formation and dynamics</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1404770112</url>
<snippet>Social networks affect many aspects of life, including the spread of diseases, the diffusion of information, the workers' productivity, and consumers' behavior. Little is known, however, about how these networks form and change. Estimating causal effects and mechanisms that drive social network formation and dynamics is challenging because of the complexity of engineering social relations in a controlled environment, endogeneity between network structure and individual characteristics, and the lack of time-resolved data about individuals' behavior. We leverage data from a sample of 1.5 million college students on Facebook, who wrote more than 630 million messages and 590 million posts over 4 years, to design a long-term natural experiment of friendship formation and social dynamics in the aftermath of a natural disaster. The analysis shows that affected individuals are more likely to strengthen interactions, while maintaining the same number of friends as unaffected individuals. Our findings suggest that the formation of social relationships may serve as a coping mechanism to deal with high-stress situations and build resilience in communities.
WOS:000355213200037
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="152">
<title>Searching for superspreaders of information in real-world social media</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep05547</url>
<snippet>A number of predictors have been suggested to detect the most influential spreaders of information in online social media across various domains such as Twitter or Facebook. In particular, degree, PageRank, k-core and other centralities have been adopted to rank the spreading capability of users in information dissemination media. So far, validation of the proposed predictors has been done by simulating the spreading dynamics rather than following real information flow in social networks. Consequently, only model-dependent contradictory results have been achieved so far for the best predictor. Here, we address this issue directly. We search for influential spreaders by following the real spreading dynamics in a wide range of networks. We find that the widely-used degree and PageRank fail in ranking users' influence. We find that the best spreaders are consistently located in the k-core across dissimilar social platforms such as Twitter, Facebook, Livejournal and scientific publishing in the American Physical Society. Furthermore, when the complete global network structure is unavailable, we find that the sum of the nearest neighbors' degree is a reliable local proxy for user's influence. Our analysis provides practical instructions for optimal design of strategies for "viral'' information dissemination in relevant applications.
WOS:000338421300002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="153">
<title>Who "Fills in" for Siblings and How? A Multilevel Analysis of Personal Network Composition and Its Relationship to Sibling Size</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1573-7861.2012.01343.x</url>
<snippet>In the midst of widespread fertility decline, I examine the relationship between sibling number and support network composition using multilevel regression on data from 25 countries. A fundamental structural effect of having fewer siblings is that individuals have a smaller pool of available close-kin alters with whom to construct support networks. Consequently, networks of people with fewer siblings should be composed of different sorts of relations. Results confirm that such compositional adjustment occurs in systematic ways. Compared to those with three or more siblings, adults with none to two siblings (as separate categories) are more likely to expect support from parents, extended kin, and close friends but not more likely to do so from spouses/partners and children. Single children are also more likely to include neighbors and have smaller-sized and/or impersonal networks. These findings contradict the primacy of familial ties in social support networks. Moreover, adjustment of support networks towards nonsibling ties occurs in culturally expected ways. Those with fewer siblings are generally only more likely to turn to ties for the types of support typically associated with those relationsparents for instrumental and financial support and friends for emotional support. Single children, however, also violate institutionalized expectations of social support by turning to ties for a wider range of social support. The results suggest that continuing declines in fertility could bring about both reinforcement and rearticulation of the sociocultural framing of close personal relationships. Moreover, consistent with recent research, the results show that personal networks are influenced more by individual-level than country-level factors.
WOS:000308092700009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="154">
<title>Effectiveness of dismantling strategies on moderated vs. unmoderated online social platforms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-71231-3</url>
<snippet>Online social networks are the perfect test bed to better understand large-scale human behavior in interacting contexts. Although they are broadly used and studied, little is known about how their terms of service and posting rules affect the way users interact and information spreads. Acknowledging the relation between network connectivity and functionality, we compare the robustness of two different online social platforms, Twitter and Gab, with respect to banning, or dismantling, strategies based on the recursive censor of users characterized by social prominence (degree) or intensity of inflammatory content (sentiment). We find that the moderated (Twitter) vs. unmoderated (Gab) character of the network is not a discriminating factor for intervention effectiveness. We find, however, that more complex strategies based upon the combination of topological and content features may be effective for network dismantling. Our results provide useful indications to design better strategies for countervailing the production and dissemination of anti-social content in online social platforms.
WOS:000571224500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="155">
<title>Judgment about knowledge importance: the roles of social referents and network structure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0018726708096638</url>
<snippet>As division of labor in a group can often lead to differences in perceptions about the importance of different knowledge bases to a group task, these differences can hinder the integration of different knowledge to solve task problems in a group. This study examines the social referents that group members turn to for judgments about knowledge importance, and the extent to which the relative influence of each referent depends on the group-level social network structure. The findings indicate that group members are more likely to have shared judgments with their cohesive and structurally equivalent referents within their advice network, and the strength of social influence form their cohesive and structurally equivalent referents is likely to depend on the advice network density at the group-level. However, there was no significant association in judgment similarity between group members and their central referents within the advice network. Overall, this study suggests that while social influence (in its most straightforward form) occurs between pairs of individuals, the strength of influence of a social referent is dependent on how social cues are distributed within the group's network structure. Theoretical and managerial implications for research on shared mental models and network theory of social influence are discussed.
WOS:000259957800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="156">
<title>Element-centric clustering comparison unifies overlaps and hierarchy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-44892-y</url>
<snippet>Clustering is one of the most universal approaches for understanding complex data. A pivotal aspect of clustering analysis is quantitatively comparing clusterings; clustering comparison is the basis for many tasks such as clustering evaluation, consensus clustering, and tracking the temporal evolution of clusters. In particular, the extrinsic evaluation of clustering methods requires comparing the uncovered clusterings to planted clusterings or known metadata. Yet, as we demonstrate, existing clustering comparison measures have critical biases which undermine their usefulness, and no measure accommodates both overlapping and hierarchical clusterings. Here we unify the comparison of disjoint, overlapping, and hierarchically structured clusterings by proposing a new element-centric framework: elements are compared based on the relationships induced by the cluster structure, as opposed to the traditional cluster-centric philosophy. We demonstrate that, in contrast to standard clustering similarity measures, our framework does not suffer from critical biases and naturally provides unique insights into how the clusterings differ. We illustrate the strengths of our framework by revealing new insights into the organization of clusters in two applications: the improved classification of schizophrenia based on the overlapping and hierarchical community structure of fMRI brain networks, and the disentanglement of various social homophily factors in Facebook social networks. The universality of clustering suggests far-reaching impact of our framework throughout all areas of science.
WOS:000471216400003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="157">
<title>Gender homophily and gender distribution in social networks: The case of older adults in long term care settings</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2022.06.005</url>
<snippet>Distinctiveness theory suggests that numeric rarity is correlated with stronger homophily. In this paper, we examine this theory by studying gender homophily in social networks of older adults. We document subjective social networks in multiple long term care settings for older adults over several time points. Homophily for each gender is estimated using exponential random graph models. We find evidence for positive homophily across all networks, and show that it is correlated to the magnitude of the female majority or male minority. Our findings empirically verify distinctiveness theory and could improve interventions to promote tie formation in social networks.
WOS:000828391400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="158">
<title>Social dynamics of core members in mixed-species bird flocks change across a gradient of foraging habitat quality</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0262385</url>
<snippet>Social associations within mixed-species bird flocks can promote information flow about food availability and provide predator avoidance benefits. The relationship between flocking propensity, foraging habitat quality, and interspecific competition can be altered by human-induced habitat degradation. Here we take a close look at sociality within two ecologically important flock-leader (core) species, the Carolina chickadee (Poecile carolinensis) and tufted titmouse (Baeolophus bicolor), to better understand how degradation of foraging habitat quality affects mixed-species flocking dynamics. We compared interactions of free ranging wild birds across a gradient of foraging habitat quality in three managed forest remnants. Specifically, we examined aspects of the social network at each site, including network density, modularity, and species assortativity. Differences in the social networks between each end of our habitat gradient suggest that elevated levels of interspecific association are more valuable in the habitat with low quality foraging conditions. This conclusion is supported by two additional findings: First, foraging height for the subordinate Carolina chickadee relative to the tufted titmouse decreased with an increase in the number of satellite species in the most disturbed site but not in the other two sites. Second, the chickadee gargle call rate, an acoustic signal emitted during agonistic encounters between conspecifics, was relatively higher at the high-quality site. Collectively, these results suggest an increase in heterospecific associations increases the value of cross-species information flow in degraded habitats.
WOS:000775890100021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="159">
<title>Modelling and predicting online vaccination views using bow-tie decomposition</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsos.231792</url>
<snippet>Social media has become increasingly important in shaping public vaccination views, especially since the COVID-19 outbreak. This paper uses bow-tie structure to analyse a temporal dataset of directed online social networks that represent the information exchange among anti-vaccination, pro-vaccination and neutral Facebook pages. Bow-tie structure decomposes a network into seven components, with two components, strongly connected component (SCC) and out-periphery component (OUT), emphasized in this paper: SCC is the largest strongly connected component, acting as an 'information magnifier', and OUT contains all nodes with a directed path from a node in SCC, acting as an 'information creator'. We consistently observe statistically significant bow-tie structures with different dominant components for each vaccination group over time. In particular, the anti-vaccination group has a large OUT, and the pro-vaccination group has a large SCC. We further investigate changes in opinions over time, as measured by fan count variations, using agent-based simulations and machine learning models. Across both methods, accounting for bow-tie decomposition better reflects information flow differences among vaccination groups and improves our opinion dynamics prediction results. The modelling frameworks we consider can be applied to any multi-stance temporal network and could form a basis for exploring opinion dynamics using bow-tie structure in a wide range of applications.
WOS:001167269900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="160">
<title>Measuring changes in interagency collaboration: An examination of the Bridgeport safe start initiative</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.evalprogplan.2007.04.001</url>
<snippet>This paper describes the evaluation of interagency collaboration in a network of child-serving providers as part of the evaluation of the Bridgeport Safe Start Initiative (BSSI). In line with the system of care approach, the objectives of BSSI included reducing fragmentation of efforts and delivering integrated services to families of young children exposed to or at risk of exposure to family violence. Interagency collaboration was examined via social network and focus group data collected at three time points starting at baseline. Network analysis findings suggest that over time the network structure became consistent with BSSI's vision of an ideal collaborative network structure. Focus group findings, however, present a more complex picture of the status of collaboration. This paper sheds light on approaches and challenges to measuring interagency collaboration in a service delivery system and communicating social network analysis findings to stakeholders in a way that is accessible and useful. (C) 2007 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000248882300007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="161">
<title>Detecting and modelling real percolation and phase transitions of information on social media</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41562-021-01090-z</url>
<snippet>Xie et al. directly observe the percolation phase transition of information on large-scale online social media and find that the positive-feedback coevolution between users' activity level and network structure greatly increases the spreading power. It is widely believed that information spread on social media is a percolation process, with parallels to phase transitions in theoretical physics. However, evidence for this hypothesis is limited, as phase transitions have not been directly observed in any social media. Here, through an analysis of 100 million Weibo and 40 million Twitter users, we identify percolation-like spread and find that it happens more readily than current theoretical models would predict. The lower percolation threshold can be explained by the existence of positive feedback in the coevolution between network structure and user activity level, such that more-active users gain more followers. Moreover, this coevolution induces an extreme imbalance in users' influence. Our findings indicate that the ability of information to spread across social networks is higher than expected, with implications for many information-spread problems.
WOS:000635851400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="162">
<title>A model for the multiplex dynamics of two-mode and one-mode networks, with an application to employment preference, friendship, and advice</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2012.05.005</url>
<snippet>We propose a new stochastic actor-oriented model for the co-evolution of two-mode and one-mode networks. The model posits that activities of a set of actors, represented in the two-mode network, co-evolve with exchanges and interactions between the actors, as represented in the one-mode network. The model assumes that the actors, not the activities, have agency. The empirical value of the model is demonstrated by examining how employment preferences co-evolve with friendship and advice relations in a group of seventy-five MBA students. The analysis shows that activity in the two-mode network, as expressed by number of employment preferences, is related to activity in the friendship network, as expressed by outdegrees. Further, advice ties between students lead to agreement with respect to employment preferences. In addition, considering the multiplexity of advice and friendship ties yields a better understanding of the dynamics of the advice relation: tendencies to reciprocation and homophily in advice relations are mediated to an important extent by friendship relations. The discussion pays attention to the implications of this study in the broader context of current efforts to model the co-evolutionary dynamics of social networks and individual behavior. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000320479500011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="163">
<title>How manufacturing industries connect cities across the world: extending research on 'multiple globalizations'</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/glob.12036</url>
<snippet>In this article, I concentrate on a macro-level analysis of inter-urban linkages in a 'world city network'. Empirical research on the formation of a world city network has mostly concentrated on global service providers. Yet, globally operating manufacturing firms also choose distinct urban regions throughout the world as locational anchoring points. In this article, using social network analysis, I present the first global-scale analysis of how manufacturing firms connected cities across the world (in 2010). To detect the differing 'sectoral profiles' and nodal centralities of cities functioning as geographical hubs of transnational production networks, it is necessary to analyse the network structure of distinct industrial subsectors within the global urban system. The data collected for analysis cover 120 top global firms from three manufacturing subsectors, of which two are analysed in more detail than the third. I then compare the nodal centralities of cities included in these subsectors' global networks with the GaWC research on the producer services sector that has been at the centre of previous analyses of the world city network. The comparison reveals the cities' differing positioning within 'multiple globalizations'. The aim of the article is to extend research on world city networks.
WOS:000332310000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="164">
<title>Combining stock-and-flow, agent-based, and social network methods to model team performance</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sdr.1613</url>
<snippet>Across disciplines, there has been an increasing interest in combining different simulation methods. Team science provides a particularly challenging context because of the interplay across levels of analysis. For example, team performance is decisively influenced by accumulated individual attributes, the interactions among individuals and emergent team structures-each of which is affected by multiple feedback loops at different levels of analysis. To address these challenges, we compare the modeling methods of stock-and-flow models, agent-based models and social network analysis to argue for the advantages of a hybrid approach to formal mathematical modeling in a team science context. We develop a proof-of-concept model, which combines aspects of all three methods, to investigate the effects of expertise, the patterns of members' interactions and diversity-based subgroups on team performance. Novel, important insights into team science theory result from this investigation, including, among others, the dynamic tradeoff between diversity and homogeneity on teams' performance and the importance of the communication network structure in affecting that tradeoff. 
WOS:000458297800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="165">
<title>The strength of a weak tie in the innovative performance of firms: A case of Korean high-tech manufacturing small and medium-sized enterprises</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/soc4.13214</url>
<snippet>This study explores whether the 'strength of weak ties' theory, derived from social network theory, can equally apply to business activities. To address this question, we conduct an empirical analysis, utilising 3-year panel data encompassing 3881 samples of Korean small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) in the high-tech manufacturing sector. The primary objective is to examine the effects of inter-corporate tie strength on innovative performance. The results reveal an interesting pattern in high-tech manufacturing corporations, where the strength of a tie demonstrates an inverted U-shaped relationship with an SME's patent achievement. Moreover, we observe that the effect of tie strength on an SME's patent achievement is positively moderated by its research and development (R&amp;D) intensity. Furthermore, when an SME maintains weak ties within its relationship with a large corporation, its innovative performance experiences a more positive impact than in cases where no relationship with a large corporation exists, or strong ties are maintained. These findings suggest that for SMEs, maintaining an appropriate level of embeddedness with large corporations is an effective strategy for generating sustained innovative performance within an environment characterised by active technological innovation and intense competition. The principal contribution of this paper lies in the empirical validation of the theory of weak ties concerning a firm's innovative performance.
WOS:001214366700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="166">
<title>Homophily Among Good Friends. Close and Weak Friendships Between Children With Migration Background and Native Peers</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Modifying M. Granovetters distinction between strong and weak tie friendships, social assimilation of immigrant children will be investigated from a social network perspective. Using data from primary school classes we start from the assumption that particularly close friendships have a positive impact on the process of acculturation. We investigate the role of ethnic homophily in the formation of weak and close friendships between immigrant and native children. In doing so, alternative explanations of friendship formation like social homophily as a mediator of ethnic homophily will be considered measured by similarity of ego and alter in terms of cultural capital "in the objectified state". As a result, immigrant children of Turkish origin have friendships with native peers, but these connections tend to be rather weak tie relations. Dyads of two Turkish children, in contrast, chances of close friendships are higher. It will be argued that these results are in line with the concept of selective acculturation of immigrant children of Turkish origin.
WOS:000291772200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="167">
<title>Social context, spatial structure and social network structure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2010.09.002</url>
<snippet>Frequently, social networks are studied in their own right with analyses devoid of contextual details. Yet contextual features - both social and spatial - can have impacts on the networks formed within them. This idea is explored with five empirical networks representing different contexts and the use of distinct modeling strategies. These strategies include network visualizations, QAP regression, exponential random graph models, blockmodeling and a combination of blockmodels with exponential random graph models within a single framework. We start with two empirical examples of networks inside organizations. The familiar Bank Wiring Room data show that the social organization (social context) and spatial arrangement of the room help account for the social relations formed there. The second example comes from a police academy where two designed arrangements, one social and one spatial, powerfully determine the relational social structures formed by recruits. The next example is an inter-organizational network that emerged as part of a response to a natural disaster where features of the improvised context helped account for the relations that formed between organizations participating in the search and rescue mission. We then consider an anthropological example of signed relations among sub-tribes in the New Guinea highlands where the physical geography is fixed. This is followed by a trading network off the Dalmatian coast where geography and physical conditions matter. Through these examples, we show that context matters by shaping the structure of networks that form and that a variety of network analytic tools can be mobilized to reveal how networks are shaped, in part, by social and spatial contexts. Implications for studying social networks are suggested. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000300131600004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="168">
<title>Positive Emotions, Instrumental Resources, and Organizational Network Evolution: Theorizing via Simulation Research</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2020.08.007</url>
<snippet>In the workplace, people seek positive emotional experiences as well as instrumental resources while doing their work. Yet we know little about how affective micro-dynamics drive the evolution of organizational networks, influence network trajectories, and determine macro outcomes such as collective affect and overall network structure. Given the lack of theory on affective micro-dynamics and network evolution, we propose a model that includes both affective and instrumental micro-mechanisms and use simulation methods to explore evolutionary dynamics and develop new theory. The core of our model is the empirically observed tendency for people forego the acquisition of instrumental resources to avoid a decrease in positive emotion when choosing inter-action partners. We conduct "experiments" with the simulation, considering the effects of the tradeoff, dispositional affect, resource inequality, and ingroup favoritism. The results show that dispositional affect and the tradeoff have considerable effects on network trajectories, collective affect, and resource transfer. We provide new theoretical propositions about affect in organizations.
WOS:000591504700008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="169">
<title>(Net)Working out: social capital in a private health club</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-4446.2008.00204.x</url>
<snippet>In Bowling Alone Robert Putnam considers the possibility that the growth of private health clubs and the rising rates of membership to such clubs might represent a counter-trend to his thesis on the decline in social capital. In this paper I explore this idea using ethnographic data and social network analysis. I show both that and how networks form in health clubs and I discuss the ways in which these networks constitute social capital for their members. In addition, however, I explore the 'dark side' of this form of social capital. I argue that high integration amongst some members of a fitness class can generate a power differential between those members and other, less integrated members who experience this negatively. Furthermore, with an eye on Burt's (2005) important thesis on brokerage and closure, I argue that brokerage between relatively closed clusters of agents can lead to inter-group rivalry and conflict, which, in turn, is experienced negatively by those involved.
WOS:000258683000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="170">
<title>CENTRALITY AND THE STRUCTURE OF URBAN INTERACTION - MEASURES, CONCEPTS, AND APPLICATIONS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/2579964</url>
<snippet>Although social network analysis has provided many measures of network position, these are rarely applied to spatial networks. Sociological measures of network structure were constructed to reflect binary interactions and such measures were of limited use in analysis of urban systems. Recently, several measures have been refined to accommodate the asymmetric continuous flows of people and information across space, making them appropriate for urban models. In this article, we evaluate the applicability of graph theoretic measures to the urban system. We find that graph theoretic conceptualizations of centrality are consistent with theoretical specifications of urban hierarchy. We then apply centrality measures to simulated and actual urban systems. We conclude that such measures elucidate key substantive issues relevant to increasingly complex sociospatial structures.
WOS:A1992JR10400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="171">
<title>VOTE BUYING IN INDONESIA: CANDIDATE STRATEGIES, MARKET LOGIC AND EFFECTIVENESS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/jea.2016.31</url>
<snippet>What underlying logic explains candidate participation in vote buying, given that clientelist exchange is so difficult to enforce? We address this question through close analysis of campaigns by several dozen candidates in two electoral districts in Java, Indonesia. Analyzing candidates' targeting and pricing strategies, we show that candidates used personal brokerage structures that drew on social networks to identify voters and deliver payments to them. But these candidates achieved vote totals averaging about one quarter of the number of payments they distributed. Many candidates claimed to be targeting loyalists, suggestive of "turnout buying," but judged loyalty in personal rather than partisan terms, and extended their vote-buying reach through personal connections mediated by brokers. Candidates were market sensitive, paying prices per vote determined not only by personal resources, but also by constituency size and prices offered by competitors. Accordingly, we argue that a market logic structures Indonesia's system of vote buying.
WOS:000395495700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="172">
<title>Social Support and the Religious Dimensions of Close Ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jssr.12134</url>
<snippet>Despite the influence of social support on physical and mental health, few studies have examined why some close ties are more supportive than others. Though religion provides a rich context for social interaction and a meaningful social identity, it has received little attention in the social support literature. A growing literature on religion and health offers insight into how religion affects social support processes. Using dyadic network data derived from the nationally representative 2006 Portraits of American Life Study, I examine how the religious dimensions of close, nonhousehold ties relate to provision of social support. Results from logistic regression analyses indicate that (controlling for a range of other social tie characteristics) same-faith ties are significantly more likely to be sources of help in times of need, while religious discussion is a strong predictor of receiving both help and advice. The effect of religious homophily is strongest for evangelical Protestants and African-American Protestants. My findings underscore the need for social support researchers to consider the role of religion in shaping support processes in close relationships.
WOS:000341872000009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="173">
<title>Genotyping Oral Commensal Bacteria to Predict Social Contact and Structure</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0160201</url>
<snippet>Social network structure is a fundamental determinant of human health, from infectious to chronic diseases. However, quantitative and unbiased approaches to measuring social network structure are lacking. We hypothesized that genetic relatedness of oral commensal bacteria could be used to infer social contact between humans, just as genetic relatedness of pathogens can be used to determine transmission chains of pathogens. We used a traditional, questionnaire survey-based method to characterize the contact network of the School of Public Health at a large research university. We then collected saliva from a subset of individuals to analyze their oral microflora using a modified deep sequencing multilocus sequence typing (MLST) procedure. We examined micro-evolutionary changes in the S. viridans group to uncover transmission patterns reflecting social network structure. We amplified seven housekeeping gene loci from the Streptococcus viridans group, a group of ubiquitous commensal bacteria, and sequenced the PCR products using next-generation sequencing. By comparing the generated S. viridans reads between pairs of individuals, we reconstructed the social network of the sampled individuals and compared it to the network derived from the questionnaire survey-based method. The genetic relatedness significantly (p-value &lt; 0.001) correlated with social distance in the questionnaire-based network, and the reconstructed network closely matched the network derived from the questionnaire survey-based method. Oral commensal bacterial are thus likely transmitted through routine physical contact or shared environment. Their genetic relatedness can be used to represent a combination of social contact and shared physical space, therefore reconstructing networks of contact. This study provides the first step in developing a method to measure direct social contact based on commensal organism genotyping, potentially capable of unmasking hidden social networks that contribute to pathogen transmission.
WOS:000384328500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="174">
<title>Reciprocation under status ambiguity: How dominance motives and spread of status value shape gift exchange</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2016.08.004</url>
<snippet>How does status ambiguity affect reciprocation in gift exchange? We argue that actors in an exchange relationship delay reciprocation as a means of subtly claiming dominance when relative status is ambiguous. Using a two-step link-tracing sample of gift exchange dyads from an online social network site in the early days of social media, we analyze the probability of two-way exchange dyads and the timing of reciprocation while accounting for the nested and autocorrelated data structure. The results support the predicted inverted-U shape relationship between the hazard of reciprocation and status difference. This pattern is strongest when actors lack common foci of interaction from which relative status could be gauged accurately. In addition, a higher status individual tends to delay reciprocation longer than a lower-status individual, a finding consistent with the status competition explanation. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000389730200012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="175">
<title>Status Homophily, Sexual Identity, and Lesbian Social Ties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00918369.2013.819244</url>
<snippet>The literature on friendship and social networks finds that individuals form social ties with people who are like thema much studied concept called homophily. However, few studies have explicitly examined sexual identity as a point of homophily. Scholars from multiple disciplines have long argued that sexuality influences the organization of our social worlds, yet most studies of friendship and social networks under-examine or overlook the influence of sexual identity. This study addresses that gap by looking at status homophily among lesbian social ties to examine the influence of sexual identity, as well as gender, race, class, and family, on their personal networks. Using survey data from 544 U.S. lesbian respondents, the findings make visible some of the factors and forces that shape social ties for lesbians. The results point to the importance of sexuality as an organizing element of social life, and suggest that studies that examine social networks or friendships more often make sexual identity, gender, and intersecting social locations a central focus.
WOS:000324670000006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="176">
<title>Forecasting Changes in Religiosity and Existential Security with an Agent-based Model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.18564/jasss.3596</url>
<snippet>We employ existing data sets and agent-based modeling to forecast changes in religiosity and existential security among a collective of individuals overtime. Existential security reflects the extent of economic, socioeconomic and human development provided by society. Our model includes agents in social networks interacting with one another based on the education level of the agents, the religious practices of the agents, and each agent's existential security within their natural and social environments. The data used to inform the values and relationships among these variables is based on rigorous statistical analysis of the International Social Survey Programme Religion Module (ISSP) and the Human Development Report (HDR). We conduct an evaluation that demonstrates, for the countries and time periods studied, that our model provides a more accurate forecast of changes in existential security and religiosity than two alternative approaches. The improved accuracy is largely due to the inclusion of social networks with educational homophily which alters the way in which religiosity and existential security change in the model. These dynamics grow societies where two individuals with the same initial religious practices (or belief In God, or supernatural beliefs) evolve differently based on the educational backgrounds of the individuals with which they surround themselves. Finally, we discuss the limitations of our model and provide direction for future work.
WOS:000426760200009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="177">
<title>Climate-Change Communication Within Public Natural Resource Agencies: Lessons Learned From the US Forest Service</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/08941920.2015.1107790</url>
<snippet>By analyzing interview and survey data from U.S. Forest Service employees, we examined the strategies used for communicating about climate change within the agency and their effectiveness from the perspective of agency employees. We found a limited awareness among employees regarding climate policy. We found that horizontal information flow through informal social networks was an important way in which climate-change information was communicated. We also found a lack of confidence among employees in their ability to provide feedback to agency leadership. Our results suggest that (1) agency leadership's ability to set priorities and deliver positive vision is important for increasing employee awareness and inspiring actions, (2) the agency could play a role in facilitating formal and informal networking among employees, and (3) using advanced information technologies may contribute to information flow horizontally and vertically, formally and informally.
WOS:000378710900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="178">
<title>Bridging the parochial divide: Outsider brokerage in mafia families</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ssresearch.2023.102913</url>
<snippet>How do groups maintain internal solidarity and closure without compromising their access to diverse networks? A long line of previous research suggests focusing on the boundary-spanning activities of "brokers" who bridge gaps in social structure. In many contexts, however, brokers are viewed with suspicion and distrust rather than rewarded for their diversity of interests. This article examines groups in which the theoretical deck is seemingly stacked against brokerage and toward parochialism: American-Italian mafia families. Through an institutional analysis of the mafia organization, I trace how ethnic and organizational closure led marginalized actors to seek alternative paths to enrichment beyond the family-controlled networks and industries. Using a historical network data set, I document a division of network labor in which ethnic outsiders- more than other actors-benefited as bridges between parochial organizations. This illuminates a broader paradox of social organization: while social closure is typically thought important because it increases the group's power over individual members and reinforces boundaries, it can also undermine those same boundaries by pushing marginal actors to seek opportunities and connections outside the group.
WOS:001054077000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="179">
<title>Fear of predation drives stable and differentiated social relationships in guppies</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep41679</url>
<snippet>Social relationships can have important consequences for fitness in animals. Whilst numerous studies have shown that individuals often join larger groups in response to perceived predation risk (i.e. fear of predation), the importance of predation risk in driving the formation and stability of social relationships within groups has been relatively ignored. We experimentally tested how predation threat influenced fine-scale social network structure using Trinidadian guppies (Poecilia reticulata). When perceived predation risk was high, individuals developed stable and more differentiated social ties compared to when perceived risk was low. Intriguingly, social differentiation coincided with shoals being somewhat smaller under high-perceived risk, suggesting a possible conflict between forming stable social relationships and larger social groups. Individuals most at risk of predation (large and bold individuals) showed the most exaggerated responses in several social measures. Taken together, we provide the first experimental evidence that proximate risk of predation can increase the intensity of social relationships and fine-scale social structure in animal populations.
WOS:000393650800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="180">
<title>An Experimental Study of Homophily in the Adoption of Health Behavior</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1207055</url>
<snippet>How does the composition of a population affect the adoption of health behaviors and innovations? Homophily-similarity of social contacts-can increase dyadic-level influence, but it can also force less healthy individuals to interact primarily with one another, thereby excluding them from interactions with healthier, more influential, early adopters. As a result, an important network-level effect of homophily is that the people who are most in need of a health innovation may be among the least likely to adopt it. Despite the importance of this thesis, confounding factors in observational data have made it difficult to test empirically. We report results from a controlled experimental study on the spread of a health innovation through fixed social networks in which the level of homophily was independently varied. We found that homophily significantly increased overall adoption of a new health behavior, especially among those most in need of it.
WOS:000297553600048
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="181">
<title>Social Affiliation from Religious Disaffiliation: Evidence of Selective Mixing Among Youth with No Religious Preference During the Transition to College</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jssr.12227</url>
<snippet>The number of individuals claiming a nonreligious identity in the United States is on the rise, with one-fourth of the overall U.S. public failing to identify with any of the major religious traditions. In this article, we examine whether religious disaffiliation structures social network formation in a social context in which religious identification (and religiosity) is a salient cultural marker. We take advantage of unique data on the personal networks of youth transitioning into a college where religion is a culturally salient facet of everyday life. We hypothesize that, if there is nonreligious homophily, it may result from an attraction of the disaffiliated to each other or from a repulsion away from the religiously affiliated. Results of exponential random graph models suggest that both mechanisms may be at play. We find that religious Nones and affiliated non-Catholics are disproportionately more likely to form and maintain relationships with one another and are relatively less likely to form and maintain relationships with members of their respective religious out-groups. We close by outlining the implications of our findings and delineating promising avenues for future research.
WOS:000374760300013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="182">
<title>The impact of CEO characteristics on the international entrepreneurship of small island- based firms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.24043/isj.406</url>
<snippet>This paper examines the impact of CEO characteristics on the International Entrepreneurship (IE) of listed island-based firms (IBFs) during the period 2009-2018. The research considers 164 companies from a sample of eight small islands with securities exchanges including more than one firm headquartered on the island. The selected islands are: Barbados, Cyprus, Fiji, Iceland, Jamaica, Malta, Mauritius, and Trinidad &amp; Tobago. Framed on the upper echelons theory and social network theory, the influence on IE of CEO's tenure, academic background and achievement, family allegiance, and international exposure is studied, taking into account the small island particularities. Through a binary probit model, it is concluded that CEOs' family allegiance, tenure, and academic background (if the CEO majored in Business Administration, Finance, Accounting, or Economics) are negatively related with IE, while CEOs' academic achievement and international exposure are positively associated with IE. Some of these results are atypical in the existing literature; nevertheless, islandness can explain these results. The conclusions attained suggest new theoretical and empirical lines of IE research for IBFs.
WOS:000886413400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="183">
<title>Who Received Informal Social Support During the First COVID-19 Lockdown in Germany, and Who Did Not? The Role of Social Networks, Life Course and Pandemic-Specific Risks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11205-022-02890-0</url>
<snippet>In this article, we study the receipt of informal support during the first wave of the COVID-19 pandemic in Germany. The containment measures have had various, far-reaching consequences for the wellbeing of people, creating demands for economic, practical, and emotional support-even among individuals who hitherto were not in need of support. Existing research has shown substantial levels of informal support during the pandemic, often based on individuals' existing social networks, but has predominantly taken the perspective of donors. In this article, we focus on the "demand" or recipient "side" of informal support, and ask: (1) Who receives which type of informal social support during the pandemic? (2) Who reports unmet need? (3) Which factors explain support receipt, unmet need and the type of support received? To explain patterns of receiving social support, we identify "classic" life course and "new" pandemic-specific risks and complement this perspective with individuals' support potentials from their social networks. Empirically, we use data from an online survey, collected among a quota sample of the German population (n = 4,496) at the end of the first lockdown in late spring 2020. Our analysis shows that one in six respondents received social support, while only 3&#37; report unmet need. Practical and emotional support are most widespread. Using logistic and multinomial logistic regression models our results show that social support in general and the type of support received can be explained by life course and pandemic risks, while unmet need is mainly a consequence of social network structure.
WOS:000768624900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="184">
<title>Entangling Mobility and Interactions in Social Media</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0092196</url>
<snippet>Daily interactions naturally define social circles. Individuals tend to be friends with the people they spend time with and they choose to spend time with their friends, inextricably entangling physical location and social relationships. As a result, it is possible to predict not only someone's location from their friends' locations but also friendship from spatial and temporal co-occurrence. While several models have been developed to separately describe mobility and the evolution of social networks, there is a lack of studies coupling social interactions and mobility. In this work, we introduce a model that bridges this gap by explicitly considering the feedback of mobility on the formation of social ties. Data coming from three online social networks (Twitter, Gowalla and Brightkite) is used for validation. Our model reproduces various topological and physical properties of the networks not captured by models uncoupling mobility and social interactions such as: i) the total size of the connected components, ii) the distance distribution between connected users, iii) the dependence of the reciprocity on the distance, iv) the variation of the social overlap and the clustering with the distance. Besides numerical simulations, a mean-field approach is also used to study analytically the main statistical features of the networks generated by a simplified version of our model. The robustness of the results to changes in the model parameters is explored, finding that a balance between friend visits and long-range random connections is essential to reproduce the geographical features of the empirical networks.
WOS:000333352800083
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="185">
<title>Understanding information propagation on online social tagging systems: a case study on Flickr</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11135-012-9799-8</url>
<snippet>Online social networking services (SNS) have been regarded as one of the most powerful online communication channels to propagate information to other users. It means that the online social networking services are providing users with efficient features (e.g., searching, managing and visualizing new information). It is important for many online collaborative applications to understand how the information can be propagated via such social media. Thus, we want to focus on a social tagging system (e.g., Flickr) where users can easily exchange resources as well as their tags. In this paper, given a certain tag, a social pulse can be established by counting (i) the number of users and (ii) the number of resources over time. More importantly, we assume that information can be propagated by (iii) inducibility from other tags by comparing social pulses. To conduct experimentation, a tag-based searching system (called Tagoole) has been implemented to collect a dataset from Flickr.
WOS:000330996000012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="186">
<title>Gender inequities in the online dissemination of scholars' work</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2102945118</url>
<snippet>Unbiased science dissemination has the potential to alleviate some of the known gender disparities in academia by exposing female scholars' work to other scientists and the public. And yet, we lack comprehensive understanding of the relationship between gender and science dissemination online. Our largescale analyses, encompassing half a million scholars, revealed that female scholars' work is mentioned less frequently than male scholars' work in all research areas. When exploring the characteristics associated with online success, we found that the impact of prior work, social capital, and gendered tie formation in coauthorship networks are linked with online success for men, but not for women-even in the areas with the highest female representation. These results suggest that while men's scientific impact and collaboration networks are associated with higher visibility online, there are no universally identifiable facets associated with success for women. Our comprehensive empirical evidence indicates that the gender gap in online science dissemination is coupled with a lack of understanding the characteristics that are linked with female scholars' success, which might hinder efforts to close the gender gap in visibility.
WOS:000708052600020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="187">
<title>Suicide Ideation of Individuals in Online Social Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0062262</url>
<snippet>Suicide explains the largest number of death tolls among Japanese adolescents in their twenties and thirties. Suicide is also a major cause of death for adolescents in many other countries. Although social isolation has been implicated to influence the tendency to suicidal behavior, the impact of social isolation on suicide in the context of explicit social networks of individuals is scarcely explored. To address this question, we examined a large data set obtained from a social networking service dominant in Japan. The social network is composed of a set of friendship ties between pairs of users created by mutual endorsement. We carried out the logistic regression to identify users' characteristics, both related and unrelated to social networks, which contribute to suicide ideation. We defined suicide ideation of a user as the membership to at least one active user-defined community related to suicide. We found that the number of communities to which a user belongs to, the intransitivity (i.e., paucity of triangles including the user), and the fraction of suicidal neighbors in the social network, contributed the most to suicide ideation in this order. Other characteristics including the age and gender contributed little to suicide ideation. We also found qualitatively the same results for depressive symptoms.
WOS:000318343700044
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="188">
<title>Structure and emergence in a nested logit model with social and spatial interactions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10588-013-9157-y</url>
<snippet>Suppose you have the possibility to choose to adopt one of a number of different behaviors or to choose to buy one of a number of different products, and suppose your choice is influenced by your individual perception of the average choices made by others. Economists Brock and Durlauf (in Am. Econ. Rev. 92(2):298, 2002; The Economy as an Evolving Complex System III. Oxford University Press, New York, 2006) have derived seminal theoretical results for the equilibrium behavior of the multinomial discrete choice model with social interactions, assuming homogeneous decision-makers, global interactions and laws of large of numbers. The research presented in this paper extends Brock and Durlauf's model to allow for unobserved preference heterogeneity between choice alternatives by studying the nested logit model. Next, by drawing on the computational possibilities permitted through social simulation of multi-agent systems (MAS), this paper relaxes the assumption of global interactions and considers instead local interactions within several hypothesized social and spatial network structures. Additional heterogeneity is thus hereby induced by the influence on a given decision-maker's choice by the particular network connections he or she has and the particular perceived percentages, for example, of the agent's neighbors or socio-economic peers making each choice. Discrete choice estimation results controlling these heterogeneous individual preferences are embedded in a multi-agent based simulation model in order to observe the evolution of choice behavior over time with socio-dynamic feedback due to the network effects. The MAS approach also gives us an additional advantage in the possibility to test size effects, and thus relax the assumption of large numbers, as well as test the effect of different initial conditions. Finally an extra benefit is gained via the MAS approach in that we are not confined to study only the equilibrium behavior, and have the possibility here to observe the time-varying trajectories of the choice behavior. This is important since smaller network sizes are revealed to be associated with higher volatility of the choice behavior in this model, and consequently stochastic cycling between equilibria. Averaged over time, the emergent behavior in such case yields a quite different picture than the theoretical results predicted by Brock and Durlauf. Furthermore being able to observe the emergent behavior allows us to see the subtle role of the unobserved heterogeneity in the nested logit model in breaking the symmetry of the multinomial logit model. We can see the temporal patterns by which theoretically predicted dominant equilibria emerge or not according to different social and spatial network scenarios. With an eye towards application in the context of transportation mode choice, we conclude highlighting limitations of our present study and recommendations for future work.
WOS:000319511300004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="189">
<title>Finding College Student Social Networks by Mining the Records of Student ID Transactions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/sym11030307</url>
<snippet>Information about college students' social networks plays a pivotal role in college students' mental health monitoring and student management. While there have been many studies to infer social networks by data mining, the mining of college students' social networks lacks consideration of homophily. College students' social behaviors show significant homophily in the aspect of major and grade. Consequently, the inferred inter-major and inter-grade social ties will be erroneously omitted without considering such an effect. In this work, we aimed to increase the fidelity of the extracted networks by alleviating the homophily effect. To achieve this goal, we propose a method that combines the sliding time-window method with the hierarchical encounter model based on association rules. Specifically, we first calculated the counts of spatial-temporal co-occurrences of each student pair. The co-occurrences were acquired by the sliding time-window method, which takes advantage of the symmetry of the social ties. We then applied the hierarchical encounter model based on association rules to extract social networks by layer. Furthermore, we propose an adaptive method to set co-occurrence thresholds. Results suggested that our model infers the social networks of students with better fidelity, with the proportion of extracted inter-major social ties in entire social ties increasing from 0.89&#37; to 5.45&#37; and the proportion of inter-grade social ties rising from 0.92&#37; to 4.65&#37;.
WOS:000464404500006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="190">
<title>A Social Science-Inspired Complexity Policy: Beyond the Mantra of Incentivization</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cplx.21520</url>
<snippet>This study suggests that cross-fertilization between complexity and social science could provide a new rationale for policy. We look at the weakness of conventional policy thinking and excessive faith in incentives and the underestimation of social interaction on individual choices. Recent examples of experimental and computational research on social interaction indicate the importance of understanding preexisting social norms and network structures for targeting appropriately contextualized policies. This would allow us to conceive policy not as something that takes place "off-line'' outside systems but as a constitutive process interacting with self-organized system behavior. This article aims to pave the way for a complexity-friendly policy that allows us to understand and manage more than predict and control top-down. (C) 2014 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.
WOS:000339548700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="191">
<title>Linked lives and convoys of social relations</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.alcr.2022.100502</url>
<snippet>We consider linked lives through the Convoy Model of Social Relations to illustrate their complexity, consequences, and development across contexts. To illustrate how the Convoy Model lens provides a unique opportunity to examine the multidimensional and dynamic character of linked lives across time and space, we analyze twenty-three years of longitudinal data from the Social Relations Study (SRS). The SRS is a regionally representative Detroit-area sample (N=1,498) with three waves (1992; 2005; 2015) of data from community dwelling people age 13 to 93. We present three illustrative examples of linked lives: 1) the influence of earlier life social network characteristics (size and closeness) on later life health outcomes; 2) the influence of social position (race and education) on relationship quality with spouse/partner and child over time; and 3) the influence of transitioning from working to retirement on network structure (size and geographic proximity). Findings illustrate linked lives through multiple instances of social relationships and as influenced by various contexts. Further, the consequences of linked lives for mental health are consistent across the life course while influence on physical health is variable. The Convoy Model presents key concepts to situate the ways in which linked lives form and function at various levels and across multiple contexts to have far reaching effects on life outcomes.
WOS:000861511700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="192">
<title>Extrapolative simulation of neighborhood networks based on population spatial distribution: Do they predict crime?</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2013.07.002</url>
<snippet>Objectives: Previous criminological scholarship has posited that network ties among neighborhood residents may impact crime rates, but has done little to consider the specific ways in which network structure may enhance or inhibit criminal activity. A lack of data on social ties has arguably led to this state of affairs. We propose to avoid this limitation by demonstrating a novel approach of extrapolatively simulating network ties and constructing structural network measures to assess their effect on neighborhood crime rates. Methods: We first spatially locate the households of a city into their constituent blocks. Then, we employ spatial interaction functions based on prior empirical work and simulate a network of social ties among these residents. From this simulated network, we compute network statistics that more appropriately capture the notions of cohesion and information diffusion that underlie theories of networks and crime. Results: We show that these network statistics are robust predictors of the levels of crime in five separate cities (above standard controls) at the very micro geographic level of blocks and block groups. Conclusions: We conclude by considering extensions of the approach that account for homophily in the formation of network ties. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000328713500010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="193">
<title>Who runs the arts in England? A social network analysis of arts boards</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.poetic.2022.101646</url>
<snippet>Recent research on cultural production has drawn attention to significant inequalities. This paper aims to unpack one possible explanation for these inequalities by focusing on the people with ultimate responsibility for arts institutions: the boards of directors. Using data from the UK's Companies House, it analyses the boards of Arts Council England's National Portfolio Organisations. It then "hops" to the other organisations with whom arts organisations also share board members, and their directors. While the network of NPOs is relatively sparse, with most organisations not sharing board members with any others, in the one-hop network the majority of these organisations are indirectly connected to one another. In addition to a large number of arts and cultural organisations, this network also contains a large proportion of film funding companies and financial services companies. The most central company in the network, measured by betweenness, is the Royal Opera House, followed by companies associated with significant tax advantages for their directors. Our results raise questions for the governance of culture, drawing further attention to its ties with financial institutions.
WOS:000832837800011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="194">
<title>RETRACTED: Mediating Effect of Organizational Learning Capacity on the Relationship between Relational Embeddedness and Innovation Performance in Freight Logistics Service (Retracted Article)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2021/5516599</url>
<snippet>Cooperative innovation has become a critical method for freight logistics firms in supply chain management. The previous study has proved that relational embeddedness (RE) has a positive effect on service innovation performance. However, the influence of organizational learning capacity (OLC) has been widely ignored. This study focuses on explaining the mechanism of OLC on the relationship between RE and innovation performance of freight logistics service (IPFLS). Firstly, a theoretical model is constructed based on Social Network Theory, and four research hypotheses are presented. Secondly, a sample of 236 respondents from freight logistics firms in China is analyzed to test the hypotheses. Finally, several management implications and recommendations are suggested. The research results demonstrate that both RE and OLC have positive effects on IPFLS. Meanwhile, OLC partially mediates the relationship between RE and IPFLS. The findings provide practical guidance for managers to strengthen the relationship with partners and enhance OLC.
WOS:000664863500009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="195">
<title>Connected seniors: how older adults in East York exchange social support online and offline</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2017.1305428</url>
<snippet>How do older adults mobilize social support, with and without digital media? To investigate this, we focus on older adults 65+ residing in the Toronto locality of East York, using 42 interviews lasting about 90 minutes done in 2013-2014. We find that digital media help in mobilizing social support as well as maintaining and strengthening existing relationships with geographically near and distant contacts. This is especially important for those individuals (and their network members) who have limited mobility. Once older adults start using digital media, they become routinely incorporated into their lives, used in conjunction with the telephone to maintain existing relationships but not to develop new ones. Contradicting fears that digital media are inadequate for meaningful relational contact, we found that these older adults considered social support exchanged via digital media to be real support that cannot be dismissed as token. Older adults especially used and valued digital media for companionship. They also used them for coordination, maintaining ties, and casual conversations. Email was used more with friends than relatives; some Skype was used with close family ties. Our research suggests that policy efforts need to emphasize the strengthening of existing networks rather than the establishment of interventions that are outside of older adults' existing ties. Our findings also show that learning how to master technology is in itself a form of social support that provides opportunities to strengthen the networks of older adults.
WOS:000400011000004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="196">
<title>THE ROLE OF TASTE AFFINITY IN AGENT-BASED MODELS FOR SOCIAL RECOMMENDATION</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0219525913500094</url>
<snippet>In the Internet era, online social media emerged as the main tool for sharing opinions and information among individuals. In this work, we study an adaptive model of a social network where directed links connect users with similar tastes, and over which information propagates through social recommendation. Agent-based simulations of two different artificial settings for modeling user tastes are compared with patterns seen in real data, suggesting that users differing in their scope of interests is a more realistic assumption than users differing only in their particular interests. We further introduce an extensive set of similarity metrics based on users' past assessments, and evaluate their use in the given social recommendation model with both artificial simulations and real data. Superior recommendation performance is observed for similarity metrics that give preference to users with small scope-who thus act as selective filters in social recommendation.
WOS:000326721000004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="197">
<title>Privacy-Preserving Discovery of Topic-Based Events from Social Sensor Signals: An Experimental Study on Twitter</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/204785</url>
<snippet>Social network services (e. g., Twitter and Facebook) can be regarded as social sensors which can capture a number of events in the society. Particularly, in terms of time and space, various smart devices have improved the accessibility to the social network services. In this paper, we present a social software platform to detect a number of meaningful events from information diffusion patterns on such social network services. The most important feature is to process the social sensor signal for understanding social events and to support users to share relevant information along the social links. The platform has been applied to fetch and cluster tweets from Twitter into relevant categories to reveal hot topics.
WOS:000334199100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="198">
<title>Crafting Mosaics: Person-Centered Religious Influence and Selection in Adolescent Friendships</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jssr.12638</url>
<snippet>This research addresses the intersection of two key domains of adolescents' lives: religion and peer networks. Religion scholars argue that religion is multi-faceted and better understood by focusing on combinations of indicators (i.e., mosaics), versus a variable-centered approach. We adopt this framework and investigate the interplay between religion and peer networks, both in how religious mosaics are shaped by friends and how religious profiles affect friend selection dynamics. With data from two schools in the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health, we estimate religious mosaics using latent class analysis (LCA) to identify profiles consisting of combinations of commonly available survey-based measures of religious attitudes, behaviors, and identities. Finding evidence of theoretically expected profiles, we then use stochastic actor-based models (SABMs) to investigate network dynamics for these LCA-based religious profiles. We demonstrate how the profile data can be integrated within the SABM framework to evaluate processes of friend selection and influence. Results show evidence of adolescents influencing one another's religious mosaics, but not selecting friends on that basis.
WOS:000508898000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="199">
<title>Reproducing a White Elite: The Chief Officers Club in the London Metropolitan Police Service</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/09500170231199415</url>
<snippet>This article focuses on the London Metropolitan Police Service, an organization charged with being institutionally racist. It asks why the percentage of black officers in senior positions remains so low, despite explicit formal attempts to change this situation. Rather than concentrating on the factors holding back the recruitment and promotion of black officers, the article examines how senior white officers managed their career journey. Through in-depth interviews with senior officers, the authors develop the notion of ' social network volition ', linking to sociological literatures on race, social networks and elites in work and organizations. The agency of a ' club ', composed of white senior officers, performs social network volition, defined as an invisible guiding hand that identifies, pursues, advises and sponsors white officers who fit the existing leadership composition. The implications of the article underline the need to make explicit the informal supports that reproduce whiteness while upholding the myth of merit.
WOS:001071487800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="200">
<title>Integrated or isolated? The impact of public housing redevelopment on social network homophily</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2011.01.001</url>
<snippet>Do mixed income housing programs increase the poor's social network diversity? Using unique, longitudinal, egocentric social network data, this research investigates changes in social network homophily for both Vietnamese and English-speaking original residents of a public housing redevelopment site. Changes in mixing occur for both those who return and those who moved away, but only increases in ethnic mixing were associated with returning to the new site. Thus, changes in social networks may be associated with disruption rather moving to a mixed-income site. Vietnamese residents also experienced increases in ethnic diversity compared to English-speaking respondents. The results raise questions about the social mixing intent of such programs. The high expectations for social network benefits of income mixing housing programs should be tempered. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000291175400006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="201">
<title>Social networks and student activism: on the politicising effect of campus connections</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-954X.2008.00775.x</url>
<snippet>In the first part of this paper I present original survey data which suggests that the transition from further to higher education, or more specifically the process of becoming a university student, has a politicising effect upon some students. In particular, university students are more likely that their 6th form counter-parts to have engaged in some of the forms of protest activity associated with social movements. This holds even during periods when levels of social movement mobilisation are low both on and off campus. In the second part of the paper I review several of the key theoretical explanations of student politicisation to be found in the social movements literature. Having criticised these theories and noted that they are challenged by my survey findings, I outline an alternative which focuses upon campus-based social networks. University campuses, I suggest, facilitate the formation of a critical and connected mass of previously politicised actors who then use their further networks to recruit political novices into activism. It is this recruitment activity, which is greatly enhanced by the network structure of campus life, which explains the politicising effect of campus life. Moreover, insofar as new recruits go on to become recruiters this forms part of a self-perpetuating dynamic of politicisation.
WOS:000253259000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="202">
<title>Coming untied? Narrative accounts of social network dynamics from first-time mental health clients</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9566.2012.01459.x</url>
<snippet>Existing research demonstrates a relationship between mental illness and social network attrition over time a pattern attributed to dysfunctional psychosocial and interpersonal processes and rejection. Yet, according to the social network perspective, personal network dynamics naturally accompany important biographical transitions or events, suggesting that our current understanding of mechanisms underlying network instability in mental illness may be incomplete. This research uses data from the Indianapolis Network Mental Health Study, a longitudinal study of social network dynamics spanning five years. It focuses on in-depth interviews with 135 individuals making their first major contact with the mental health treatment system. First, levels of tie attrition and replacement in the core discussion networks of individuals with mental illness are compared to a sample with no self-reported history of mental illness. Second, using open-ended responses describing why specific individuals mentioned in previous waves were not listed again, respondents explanations of attrition are analysed qualitatively. In addition to providing support for existing perspectives, the themes suggest a need to also consider: (i) interaction strategies that maximise the supportiveness of social networks and minimise burden and (ii) changing life circumstances external to social networks that influence opportunities for social interaction.
WOS:000310675900001
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
